<?xml version='1.0'?><question-list type='read' passage-file='AMR02P0.xml'><question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P1.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The phrase <bg>twists and turns</bg> in paragraph 1 could best be replaced by</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>improvements in techniques</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>changes in direction</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>expressions of emotion</answer-text>         <answer-text>opinions about artists</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>2</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>in this long journey, there have been numerous twists and turns</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>twists and turns</exp> could best be replaced by <exp>changes in direction</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question><question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P2.xml" skills="5">      <question-text>It is stated in the passage that, before the seventeenth century, it was common for artists to work for</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text><exp>the nobility</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>the bourgeoisie</answer-text>         <answer-text>middlemen</answer-text>         <answer-text>bankers and financiers</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>1</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>in the era prior to the seventeenth century, the artist had toiled predominantly&#8230;in the employ of a member of the noble class</exp>. This means that, before the seventeenth century, it was common for artists to work for <exp>the nobility</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P3.xml" skills="2">      <question-text>The word <bg>it</bg> in paragraph 1 refers to</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text><exp>this new class</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>an impact</answer-text>         <answer-text>the structure</answer-text>         <answer-text>society</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>1</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>this new class&#8230;began to have an impact</exp> and that <exp>it also greatly influenced&#8230;</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>it</exp> refers to <exp>this new class</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P4.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The phrase <exp><bg>augmentation of</bg></exp> in paragraph 2 is closest in meaning to</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>production of</answer-text>         <answer-text>belief in</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>increase in</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>knowledge of</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>3</key>      <explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>the augmentation of expensive and sometimes ostentatious possessions</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>augmentation of</exp> is closest in meaning to <exp>increase in</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P5.xml" skills="6">      <question-text>It is indicated in the passage that the rise of the middle class led to all of the following EXCEPT</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text><exp>a change in the world of art</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>an increase in acquisition by the middle class</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>an increase in artists from the bourgeoisie</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>an increase in patronage of the arts by the middle class</exp></answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>3</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>with the rise of the bourgeoisie, or middle class, the nature of patronage of the arts began to change</exp>, which refers to <exp>a change in the world of art</exp> in the first answer; the passage states that <exp>the prosperous bourgeoisie loved to buy and collect possessions</exp>, which refers to <exp>an increase in acquisition by the middle class</exp> in the second answer; the passage mentions <exp>the introduction of the prosperous bourgeoisie into the role of patron of the arts</exp>, which refers to <exp>an increase in patronage of the arts by the middle class</exp> in the last answer. All of the answers EXCEPT the third answer are indicated in the passage. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P6.xml" skills="3">      <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 2?</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>The new art patron preferred art that reflected the grandiose lifestyle that he had achieved.</answer-text>         <answer-text>Art that was reflective of real people was the subject of religious art of earlier times.</answer-text>         <answer-text>The prosperous bourgeoisie liked to reflect on the grandiose and divinely religious nature of art.</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>Art began to reflect more everyday themes</exp> as a result of <exp>the patronage of the new middle class.</exp></answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>4</key>      <explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>the prosperous bourgeoisie</exp> and <exp>the art patron</exp> and the highlighted sentence states that <exp>he&#8230;liked to view art that was reflective of the people in his life or of his surroundings</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>he</exp> in the highlighted sentence refers to <exp>the patronage of the new middle class</exp> and that <exp>art that was reflective of the people in his life or of his new surroundings</exp> in the highlighted sentence means that <exp>art began to reflect more everyday themes</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P7.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The word <bg>cultivation</bg> in paragraph 3 is closest in meaning to</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>agriculture</answer-text>         <answer-text>planting</answer-text>         <answer-text>seeds</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>growth</exp></answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>4</key>      <explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>the cultivation of the arts</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>cultivation</exp> is closest in meaning to <exp>growth</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type='insert' passage-file='AMR02P8.xml' skills='4'><insert-text><b><exp>Middlemen could be any of those who came between the artist and the public</exp>, including exhibitors, dealers, agents, and critics.</b></insert-text><key>3</key><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>middlemen to assist in enabling transactions&#8230;between artists and the public at large</exp>. A sentence stating that <exp>middlemen could be any of those who came between the artist and the public</exp> would logically follow such an idea. The third square in paragraph 3 is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P9.xml" skills="8">      <question-text>The author begins paragraph 4 with <exp><bg>However</bg></exp> in order to show</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>that the development of middlemen in the world of art was an obvious result of the growth of the bourgeoisie</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>that there was a contrast between the positive function of middlemen and the negative effect of this function</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>that the system of middlemen in art was not really as weak as it appeared</answer-text>         <answer-text>that artists were always in continuous conflict with middlemen</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>2</key>      <explain-text>The last sentence of paragraph 3 states that <exp>these middlemen were needed</exp>, and the first sentence of paragraph 4 begins with <exp>however, a system dependent on middlemen&#8230;develops obvious weaknesses</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that the author begins paragraph 4 with <exp>however</exp> in order to show <exp>that there was a contrast between the positive function of middlemen and the negative effect of this function</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P10.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The phrase <bg>the arbiters of</bg> in paragraph 4 are most likely the ones who</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text><exp>decide about</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>make purchases of</answer-text>         <answer-text>decrease the value of</answer-text>         <answer-text>improve upon</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>1</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>the middlemen become the arbiters of taste</exp> and that <exp>the middlemen are the ones who decide</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>the arbiters of</exp> taste are the ones who <exp>decide about</exp> taste. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P11.xml" skills="7">      <question-text>It is implied in the passage that the author believes that</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>the system of middlemen is really beneficial to the world of art</answer-text>         <answer-text>the role of decision-making in art rightly falls to the middlemen</answer-text>         <answer-text>as art is commercialized further, there will be less need for middlemen</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>the public should decide which artists should receive public acclaim</exp></answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>4</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>the weakness of this sort of system is that it is possible the role of deciding which art and artists should be enjoyed by the public is not always the public's to decide</exp>. It is implied in this that the author believes that <exp>the public should decide which artists should receive public acclaim</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR02P12.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The phrase <bg>came to light</bg> in paragraph 4 could best be replaced by</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>were turned on</answer-text>         <answer-text>were lightened</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>were discovered</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>were praised</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>3</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>numerous examples came to light of artists who today are ranked among the world's finest but had originally been ignored</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that the phrase <exp>came to light</exp> could best be replaced by <exp>were discovered</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type='select.1' passage-file='AMR02P13.xml' skills='9'><direction-text>Select the appropriate sentences from the answer choices that are key points in a discussion of <exp>the evolution of art as a business</exp>. TWO of the answer choices will NOT be discussed. <i><b>This question is worth 3 points.</b></i></direction-text><intro-text><b>The evolution of art as a business</b></intro-text><answer-list><answer><answer-text><exp>Middlemen developed in the world of art</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage states that <exp>it became increasingly necessary for middlemen to assist in enabling transactions, not between patrons and artists but between artists and the public at large, in order for the system to function smoothly</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>middlemen developed in the world of art</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>the evolution of art as a business</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>Art became more grandiose over time</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage states that <exp>art&#8230;began to reflect less grandiose themes than the divinely religious art or the art of the nobility had in earlier times</exp>. This means that it is not true that <exp>art became more grandiose over time</exp>. This answer is therefore not a correct answer to this question.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>Middlemen became arbiters in the world of art</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>a system dependent on middlemen functioning between artists and the public</exp> and states that <exp>the middlemen become the arbiters of taste</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>middlemen became arbiters in the world of art</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>the evolution of art as a business</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>Artists were no longer interested in pleasing the public</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>It is not stated in the passage that <exp>artists were no longer interested in pleasing the public</exp>. This answer is therefore not a correct answer to this question.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>The rising middle class became patrons of the arts</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>after 1600, with the rise of the bourgeoisie</exp>, states that <exp>the prosperous bourgeoisie loved to buy and collect possessions</exp>, and mentions <exp>the introduction of the prosperous bourgeoisie into the role of patron of the arts</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>the rising middle class became patrons of the arts</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>the evolution of art as a business</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>Art tended to be more commercial than commissioned</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage states that <exp>it became increasingly necessary for middlemen to assist in enabling transactions, not between patrons and artists but between artists and the public at large, in order for the system to function smoothly</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>art tended to be more commercial than commissioned</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>the evolution of art as a business</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.</explain-text></answer></answer-list><key>1.3.02</key></question>   </question-list>   