<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage scroll0='bottom' scroll='41'>
   <passage-text>
      <div align="center"><b>Plant Distribution</b></div>
      <br/>Environmentalists have long debated the question of how change in the distribution of plant coverage takes place. This question is one that is difficult to clarify because of the complex relationships between various plant species and the environment. Numerous models have been proposed to explain the nature of change in plant distribution, though today there is fairly broad agreement that one model cannot possibly cover the various and diverse kinds of changes that take place and that, in reality, various models each help to explain some of the changes. Three of the most discussed models are the community-succession model, the individualistic model, and the disturbance model. The first of these, the community-succession model, is the one that is most often used to explain various changes in plant distribution, basically by suggesting that plants tend to move into favorable environments. However, the remaining two models offer interesting insights into some of the changes that cannot be explained by the community-succession model.<br/>
The community-succession model is based upon the idea that plants are capable of causing changes to occur in the environments that they inhabit, particularly in the climate in their immediate surroundings, the nutrient content of the soil, and the erodability of the soil. The process described in the model begins with an area that has been stripped of vegetation as the result of a natural event such as fire, flood, or glaciation. Certain hardy plants such as mosses and grasses are the first to migrate into the denuded area and, thus, are called pioneers. These initial plants cause changes in the environment, perhaps by adding nutrients to the soil or preventing erosion, and at the same time prepare the environment for a second invasion of plants. The pioneers are followed or replaced by a second group of plants, and these new plants in turn cause further changes to the environment. Each group that inhabits a particular environment together is called a community because it is made up of plants that live together in one environment. Different communities of plants continue to move into the area as changes to the environment caused by prior communities make the area more receptive to newer communities; when a state of equilibrium has been reached in the environmental system and the community is stabilized, this final group of plants is called the climax community.<br/>
The individualistic model is based on the idea that changes in the distribution of plant coverage can be explained on the basis of the probability of recurrence of individual plants rather than on the basis of the relationship of a community of plants to the environment. When a plant dies, space is opened up for another plant to move in, and it is simply a matter of probabilities as to which plant moves into the newly opened up space. The plants that have the highest probabilities of moving into the emptied space are those that are in closest proximity, those that are present in the greatest numbers, and those that are the most able to disperse themselves. Under this model, climax communities are stable because probabilities favor the recurrence of existing species and not because the optimal species for a particular environment has been achieved.<br/>
<sqr/> According to the disturbance model, the distribution of plants changes in response to <exp>negative forces in the environment of the plant</exp>. <sqr/> When the level of disturbance in the environment exceeds that which a particular plant is able to tolerate, the plants living in the area of disturbance either die or fail to reproduce and thus lose territory. <sqr/> However, the event that has caused the disturbance most likely ends, and when the disturbance is over, a different model is needed to explain what happens to plant distribution in the ensuing period of time. <sqr/><br/><br/>
 </passage-text>
</passage>