<?xml version='1.0'?><question-list type='read' passage-file='AMR01P0.xml'><question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P1.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The word <bg>fixed</bg> in paragraph 2 could best be replaced by</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>ordered</answer-text>         <answer-text>repaired</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>established</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>attached</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>3</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>his original scale had two fixed points: 0&#0186; was the lowest temperature that he could achieve in a solution of ice, water, and salt, and 96&#0186; was what he believed was the normal temperature of the human body</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>fixed</exp> could best be replaced by <exp>established</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question><question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P2.xml" skills="5">      <question-text>What is stated in the passage about the temperature scale developed by Fahrenheit?</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>On it, 0&#0186; was the freezing point of water.</answer-text>         <answer-text>It was based on the lowest and highest temperatures that he could achieve with a mixture of salt and water.</answer-text>         <answer-text>On it, 100&#0186; was the boiling point of water.</answer-text>         <answer-text>It <exp>was based on an inaccurate understanding of the normal temperature of the human body</exp>.</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>4</key>      <explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>Fahrenheit</exp> and states that <exp>his original scale&#8230;was what he believed was the normal temperature of the human body (though this was later determined to be 98.6&#0186;)</exp>. This means that the scale developed by Fahrenheit <exp>was based on an inaccurate understanding of the normal temperature of the human body</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P3.xml" skills="2">      <question-text>The word <bg>it</bg> in paragraph 2 refers to</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text><exp>the Fahrenheit scale</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>temperature</answer-text>         <answer-text>a number of countries</answer-text>         <answer-text>the world</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>1</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>the Fahrenheit scale came to be accepted</exp> and that <exp>it was spread</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>it</exp> refers to <exp>the Fahrenheit scale</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P4.xml" skills="8">      <question-text>The author refers to <bg>many other countries</bg> in paragraph 3 in order to</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>introduce a discussion of the areas of the world where the Celsius scale is used</answer-text>         <answer-text>argue for the need for a standard measure of temperature throughout the world</answer-text>         <answer-text>provide an example that demonstrates the effectiveness of the Celsius scale</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>relate the widespread use of the Celsius scale to the previously mentioned limited use of the Fahrenheit scale</exp></answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>4</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>the United States is the only major country in the world that still uses the Fahrenheit scale</exp> at the end of the second paragraph and that <exp>the scale that is in use in many other countries is the Celsius scale</exp> at the beginning of the third paragraph. From this, it can be determined that the author mentions <exp>many other countries</exp> in order to <exp>relate the widespread use of the Celsius scale to the previously mentioned limited use of the Fahrenheit scale</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P5.xml" skills="6">      <question-text>Which of the following is NOT true about the Celsius scale, according to the passage?</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>It was developed by an astronomer from Sweden.</answer-text>         <answer-text>It came into use in the eighteenth century.</answer-text>         <answer-text>One hundred degrees separated the freezing and boiling temperatures of water on it.</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>On it, 0&#0186; indicated the temperature at which water freezes.</exp></answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>4</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>on the thermometer that Celsius developed, however, 0&#0186; was used to indicate the boiling temperature of water</exp>. From this, it can be determined that it is NOT true that <exp>on it, 0&#0186; indicated the temperature at which water freezes</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P6.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The word <bg>reversed</bg> in paragraph 3 is closest in meaning to</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>brought in</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>turned around</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>thought up</answer-text>         <answer-text>sent back</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>2</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>0&#0186; was used to indicate the boiling temperature of water, and 100&#0186; was used to indicate the freezing temperature of water, </exp>that <exp>the scale was reversed</exp>, and that <exp>0&#0186; indicated the freezing temperature of water, and 100&#0186; indicated the boiling temperature of water</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>reversed</exp> is closest in meaning to <exp>turned around</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P7.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The word <bg>adopted</bg> in paragraph 3 could best be replaced by</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text><exp>taken on</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>brought up</answer-text>         <answer-text>looked upon</answer-text>         <answer-text>turned down</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>1</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>the scale developed in France was adopted as part of the metric system in&#8230;</exp>France<exp>&#8230;under the name centigrade</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>adopted</exp> could best be replaced by <exp>taken on</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question><question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P8.xml" skills="3">      <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 3?</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>The discovery of the centigrade scale in 1948 brought honor to the scientist who discovered it.</answer-text>         <answer-text>After an international organization decided to use the centigrade scale in 1948, Celsius reversed the numbers on the scale.</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>In 1948, nations agreed to name the centigrade scale</exp> after <exp>the man who developed an earlier version of the scale</exp>.</answer-text>         <answer-text>In 1948, Celsius honored the scientist who was first known to use a 100-degree scale by naming it the centigrade scale.</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>3</key>      <explain-text>The highlighted sentence states that <exp>in 1948, an international agreement was made to rename the centigrade scale</exp>, which means that <exp>in 1948, nations agreed to name the centigrade scale</exp>, and then mentions <exp>the scientist who was first known to use a 100-degree scale</exp> and states that <exp>the scale&#8230;was the reverse of today's scale</exp>, which refers to <exp>the man who developed an earlier version of the scale</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>   <question type='insert' passage-file='AMR01P9.xml' skills='4'><insert-text><b><exp>Frenchman Jean Pierre Christin</exp> (1683&#8211;1755) <exp>placed an order</exp> with instrument maker Pierre Casati <exp>for thermometers based on the same scale</exp>, with 0&#0186; indicating the freezing point of water and 100&#0186; indicating the boiling point of water.</b></insert-text><key>2</key><explain-text>The passage states that <exp>a similar thermometer was being developed in France</exp>. A sentence stating that <exp>Frenchman Jean Pierre Christin&#8230;placed an order&#8230;for thermometers based on the same scale</exp> would logically follow such an idea. The second square in paragraph 3 is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question>       <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P10.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>A <exp><bg>hypothetical</bg></exp> temperature in paragraph 4 is one that</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text><exp>is assumed to exist</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>has been found to be false</answer-text>         <answer-text>is known to be impossible</answer-text>         <answer-text>has been proved through experiments</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>1</key>      <explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>absolute zero, the hypothetical temperature at which all atomic and molecular motion theoretically stops</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that a <exp>hypothetical</exp> temperature is one that <exp>is assumed to exist</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question>             <question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P11.xml" skills="1">      <question-text>The phrase <bg>well suited to</bg> in paragraph 4 could best be replaced by</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text><exp>appropriate for</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>outfitted with</answer-text>         <answer-text>related to</answer-text>         <answer-text>in harmony with</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>1</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>the Kelvin scale is well suited to some areas of scientific study</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that the phrase <exp>well suited to</exp> could best be replaced by <exp>appropriate for</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question><question type="multichoice" passage-file="AMR01P12.xml" skills="7">      <question-text>It can be inferred from the passage that a temperature of 50&#0186; centigrade would be equal to</question-text>      <answer-list>         <answer-text>223&#0186; on the Kelvin scale</answer-text>         <answer-text>273&#0186; on the Kelvin scale</answer-text>         <answer-text><exp>323&#0186; on the Kelvin scale</exp></answer-text>         <answer-text>373&#0186; on the Kelvin scale</answer-text>      </answer-list>      <key>3</key>      <explain-text>The passage states that <exp>the Kelvin scale&#8230;can thus easily be converted to the Celsius scale by merely subtracting 273&#0186; from the temperature on the Kelvin scale</exp>. From this, it can be determined that a temperature of 50&#0186; centigrade would be equal to <exp>323&#0186; on the Kelvin scale</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text>   </question><question type='select.2' passage-file='AMR01P13.xml' skills='10'><direction-text>Select the appropriate sentences from the answer choices and match them to the temperature scales to which they relate. TWO of the answer choices will NOT be used. <i><b>This question is worth 3 points.</b></i></direction-text><key>24.0.531</key><category-list><category><category-text><b><exp>Fahrenheit scale</exp></b></category-text></category><category><category-text><b><exp>Modern Celsius scale</exp></b></category-text></category><category><category-text><b><exp>Kelvin scale</exp></b></category-text></category></category-list><answer-list><answer><answer-text><exp>Water freezes at 0&#0186; and boils at 100&#0186;</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>the thermometer that Celsius developed</exp> and states that <exp>on the new scale after the reversal by von Linne, 0&#0186; indicated the freezing temperature of water, and 100&#0186; indicated the boiling temperature of water</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>water freezes at 0&#0186; and boils at 100&#0186;</exp> on the modern Celsius scale. This answer should therefore be used to describe the <exp><b>modern Celsius scale</b></exp>.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>Water freezes at 273&#0186; and boils at 373&#0186;</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage states that <exp>on the Kelvin scale, with 0&#0186; equal to absolute zero, water freezes at 273&#0186;, and water boils at a temperature 100&#0186; higher</exp>. This means that <exp>water freezes at 273&#0186; and boils at 373&#0186;</exp> on the Kelvin scale. This answer should therefore be used to describe the <exp><b>Kelvin scale</b></exp>.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>Water freezes at 100&#0186; and boils at 0&#0186;</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage states that <exp>on the thermometer that Celsius developed, however, 0&#0186; was used to indicate the boiling temperature of water, and 100&#0186; was used to indicate the freezing temperature of water</exp> and that <exp>the scale was reversed</exp>. This means that <exp>water freezes at 100&#0186; and boils at 0&#0186;</exp> on the earlier scale developed by Celsius but NOT on the modern Celsius scale. This answer is therefore not a correct answer choice.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>Water freezes at 32&#0186; and boils at 212&#0186;</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>the Fahrenheit scale</exp> and states that <exp>based on this scale, he calculated that the freezing point (or ice point) of water was 32&#0186;; in later studies, it was determined that the boiling point of water (the steam point) was 212&#0186;</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>water freezes at 32&#0186; and boils at 212&#0186;</exp> on the Fahrenheit scale. This answer should therefore be used to describe the <exp><b>Fahrenheit scale</b></exp>.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>0&#0186; is the temperature at which saltwater boils</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>Fahrenheit</exp> and states that <exp>0&#0186; was the lowest temperature that he could achieve in a solution of ice, water, and salt</exp>. The only time that <exp>salt</exp> and <exp>water</exp> are mentioned in the passage is in relation to Fahrenheit, and 0&#0186; was a low temperature rather than a boiling temperature. This answer is therefore not a correct answer choice.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>0&#0186; is equal to absolute zero</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>the Kelvin scale, with 0&#0186; equal to absolute zero</exp>. This means that <exp>0&#0186; is equal to absolute zero</exp> on the Kelvin scale. This answer should therefore be used to describe the <exp><b>Kelvin scale</b></exp>.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>0&#0186; is equal to the freezing temperature of water</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>the thermometer that Celsius developed</exp> and states that <exp>on the new scale after the reversal by von Linne, 0&#0186; indicated the freezing temperature of water</exp>. This means that <exp>0&#0186; is equal to the freezing temperature of water</exp> on the modern Celsius scale. This answer should therefore be used to describe the <exp><b>modern Celsius scale</b></exp>.</explain-text></answer><answer><answer-text><exp>0&#0186; was what was believed to be the lowest possible temperature of a solution of saltwater and ice</exp>.</answer-text><explain-text>The passage mentions <exp>the Fahrenheit scale</exp> and states that <exp>0&#0186; was the lowest temperature that he could achieve in a solution of ice, water, and salt</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>0&#0186; was what was believed to be the lowest possible temperature of a solution of saltwater and ice</exp>. This answer should therefore be used to describe the <exp><b>Fahrenheit scale</b></exp>.</explain-text></answer></answer-list></question></question-list>   