<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>The Pulitzer Prize</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            The Pulitzer Prize came about as part of an attempt by newspaperman Joseph
        Pulitzer to upgrade the profession of journalism. Pulitzer, the owner of the <i>New York World</i>
        and the <i>St. Louis Post-Dispatch</i>, made a proposal in 1903 to Columbia University to make
        a $2 million bequest to the university for the dual purposes of establishing a school of
        journalism at the university and also establishing prizes for exceptional work in journalism
        and other fields. However, the university did not initially respond as one might expect to
        such a seemingly generous offer.
        <br/>
            Interestingly, Columbia University was not immediately amenable to the proposal by
        Pulitzer inasmuch as journalism was not held in high regard in general and Pulitzer's papers
        were more known for their sensationalization of the. news than for the high quality of the
        journalism. The trustees of the university were not at all sure that they wanted a school of
        journalism because newspaper reporting was considered more of a trade than a profession
        at the time and they did not want to decrease the academic prestige of their institution. <bg>It
        took years of discussions and negotiations before the terms for the establishment of the
        school of journalism and the prizes bearing Pulitzer's name were agreed upon, and it was
        not actually until the year after Pulitzer's death in 1911 that construction began on the
        building to house Columbia's new school of journalism.</bg> The school of journalism opened in
        1913, and the first prizes were awarded in 1917, for work done the previous year.
        <br/>
            The method for selecting Pulitzer Prize winners and the categories for prizes have
        changed slightly over the years. Today, 21 different awards are given in three different
        areas, with the majority of awards going to journalists; 14 of the 21 awards are from various
        aspects of journalism (i.e., news reporting, feature writing, cartoons, and photography), 6
        awards are given in letters (in fiction, nonfiction, history, drama, poetry, and biography), and
        1 award in music. Columbia University appoints nominating juries comprised of experts
        in each field, and the nominating juries submit these nominations for each category to the
        Pulitzer Prize Board, which makes the final decisions and awards the prizes.
    </passage-text>
</passage>

