<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Post-it Notes</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            Post-it Notes were invented in the 1970s at the 3M company in Minnesota quite by
        accident. Researchers at 3M were working on developing different types of adhesives, and
        one particularly weak adhesive, a compound of acrylate copolymer microspheres, was
        developed. Employees at 3M were asked if they could think of a use for a weak adhesive
        which, provided it did not get dirty, could be reused. One suggestion was that it could
        be applied to a piece of paper to use as a bookmark that would stay in place in a book.
        Another use was found when the product was. attached to a report that was. to be sent to
        a colleague with a request for comments on the report; the colleague made his comments
        on the paper attached to the report and returned the report The idea. for Post-it Notes was
        born.
        <br/>
            It was decided within the company that there would be a test launch of the product
        in 1977 in four American cities. <bg>Sales of this innovative product in test cities were. less
        than stellar, most likely because the product, while innovative, was also quite unfamiliar.</bg> A
        final attempt was then made in the city of Boise to introduce the product. In this attempt,
        3M salesmen gave demonstrations of the product in offices throughout Boise and gave
        away free samples of the product. When the salesmen returned a week later to the offices
        where the product had been demonstrated and given away, a huge percentage of the office
        workers, having noted how useful the simple little product could be, were interested in
        purchasing it. Over time, 3M came to understand the huge potential of this. new product,
        and over the next few decades more than 400 varieties of Post-it products-in different
        colors, shapes, and sizes-have been developed.
    </passage-text>
</passage>

