<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage scroll0='12' scroll='12'>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Competition and Cooperation</b>
        </div>
        <br/>        
            Explanations of the interrelationship between competition and cooperation have
        evolved over time. Early research into competition and cooperation defined each of them in
        terms of the distribution of rewards related to each. Competition was defined as a situation
        in which rewards are distributed unequally on the basis of performance; cooperation, on the
        other hand, was defined as a situation in which rewards are distributed equally on the basis
        of mutual interactive behavior among individuals. By this definition, a competitive situation
        requires at least one competitor to fail for each competitor that wins, while a cooperative
        situation offers a reward only if all members of the group receive it.
        <br/>
            Researchers have found definitions of competition and cooperation based upon
        rewards inadequate primarily because definitions of these two concepts based upon
        rewards depict them as opposites. In current understanding, competition is not viewed as
        the opposite of cooperation; instead, cooperation is viewed as an integral component of
        competition. Cooperation is necessary among team members, perhaps in a sporting event
        or in a political race, in order to win the competition; it is equally important to understand
        that cooperation is of great importance between teams, in that same sporting event or
        political race, inasmuch as the opposing teams need to be in agreement as to the basic
        ground rules of the game or election in order to compete.
        <br/>
            Interestingly, the word <i>competition</i> is derived from a Latin verb which means "to
        seek together." <bg>An understanding of the derivation of the word <i>competition</i> supports the
        understanding that cooperation, rather than evoking a characteristic at the opposite extreme
        of human nature from competition, is in reality a necessary factor in competition.</bg>
    </passage-text>
</passage>

