<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage mark='2'>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>The Filibuster</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            The term <i>filibuster</i> has been in use since the mid-nineteenth century to describe the
        tactic of delaying legislative action in order to prevent the passage of a bill. The word comes
        from the Dutch <i>freebooter</i>, or pirate, and most likely developed from the idea that someone
        conducting a filibuster is trying to steal away the opportunity that proponents of a bill have
        to make it successful.
        <br/>
            In the earlier history of the U.S. Congress, filibusters were used in both the House of
        Representatives and in the Senate, but they are now much more a part of the culture of the
        Senate than of the House. Because the House is a much larger body than is the Senate, the
        House now has rules which greatly limit the amount of time that each member may speak,
        which effectively serves to eliminate the filibuster as a mechanism for delaying legislation in
        the House.
        <br/>
            In the Senate, the smaller of the two bodies, there are now rules that can constrain but
        not totally eliminate filibusters. The Senate adopted its first cloture rule in 1917, a rule which
        requires a vote of two-thirds of the Senate to limit debate to one hour on each side. The
        rule was changed in 1975 and now requires a vote of three-fifths of the members to invoke
        cloture in most situations.
        <br/>
            The longest filibuster on record occurred in 1957, when Senator Strom Thurmond
        of South Carolina wanted to delay voting on civil rights legislation. The filibuster was
        conducted for twenty-four hours and 18 minutes on August 28 and 29, when Thurmond
        held the floor of the Senate by lecturing on the law and reading from court decisions and
        newspaper columns. It was his hope that this filibuster would rally opponents of civil rights
        legislation; however, two weeks after the filibuster, the Civil Rights Act of 1957 passed.
    </passage-text>
</passage>