<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage mark='2'>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Brown Dwarfs</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            A brown dwarf is a celestial body that has never quite become a star. A typical brown
        dwarf has a mass that is 8 percent or less than that of the Sun. The mass of a brown dwarf
        is too small to generate the internal temperatures capable of igniting the nuclear burning of
        hydrogen to release energy and light.
        <br/>
            A brown dwarf contracts at a steady rate, and after it has contracted as much as
        possible, a process that takes about 1 million years, it begins to cool off. Its emission of
        light diminishes with the decrease in its internal temperature, and after a period of 2 to 3
        billion years, its emission of light is so weak that it can be difficult to observe from Earth.
        <br/>
            Because of these characteristics of a brown dwarf, it can be easily distinguished
        from stars in different stages of formation. A brown dwarf is quite distinctive because its
        surface temperature is relatively cool and because its internal composition-approximately
        75 percent hydrogen-has remained essentially the same as it was when first formed. A
        white dwarf, in contrast, has gone through a long period when it burns hydrogen, followed
        by another long period in which it burns the helium created by the burning of hydrogen and
        ends up with a core that consists mostly of oxygen and carbon with a thin layer of hydrogen
        surrounding the core.
        <br/>
            It is not always as easy, however, to distinguish brown dwarfs from large planets.
        Though planets are not formed in the same way as brown dwarfs, they may in their current
        state have some of the same characteristics as a brown dwarf. The planet Jupiter, for
        example, is the largest planet in our solar system with a mass 317 times that of our planet
        and resembles a brown dwarf in that it radiates energy based on its internal energy. It is
        the mechanism by which they were formed that distinguishes a high-mass planet such as
        Jupiter from a low-mass brown dwarf.
    </passage-text>
</passage>