<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Modernism in Art</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            A proliferation of varying styles characterized the world of American art and
        architecture in the period between 1880 and the outbreak of World War II in 1939. In spite
        of the fact that these various styles often had little in common with each other, they are
        traditionally clustered under the label of <b>modernism</b>. It is thus rather difficult to give a
        precise definition of modernism, one that encompasses all the characteristics of the artists
        and architects who are commonly grouped under this label. What modernists do have in
        common is that their work contains at least one of two characteristics of modernism.
        <br/>
            One fundamental characteristic of modernism is a demonstration of progressive
        innovation. In general, a modernist is someone who tries to develop an individual style by
        adding to or improving upon the style of immediate predecessors. The modernist belief
        was in starting with the ideas of the mainstream movement and then innovating from the
        mainstream to improve upon the ideas of predecessors rather than in breaking away from
        the mainstream to create something entirely new. However, because there were varying
        ideas on what constituted the mainstream and because the potential innovations emanating
        from the mainstream were infinite, modernism under this definition could take a myriad of
        directions.
        <br/>
            A second fundamental characteristic of modernism was the belief that art could and
        should reflect the reality of modern life and would not, for example, focus on the lives of
        society's most privileged members or on otherworld entities such as angels and sprites.
        Though there was agreement among modernists as t0 the need for art to reflect modern life,
        there was far less agreement on what actually constituted modern life. Thus, modern artists
        and architects reflect very different aspects of modern life in their works.
    </passage-text>
</passage>