<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Carnivorous Plants</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            Unlike the majority of plants that create their nourishment from sunlight, such as the
        ffowering hyacinth or the leafy choleus or the garden-variety dandelion, a limited number
        of plants are able to enhance their diet by fortifying it with insects and other small animals
        to supplement the food that they have produced from sunlight. These carnivorous plants
        can be categorized as those without moving traps that lure their intended victims and then
        trap them on a sticky surface or drown them in a pool of fluid and those with active trapsmoving
        parts that ensnare prey.
        <br/> 
            Butterworts are harmless-looking plants with circles of flat and sticky leaves. If an
        insect is unfortunate enough to land on one of the seemingly inviting leaves, it sticks to the
        surface of the leaf and eventually dies and is digested by the plant.
        <br/> 
            The pitcher plant is a plant that is shaped like a pitcher and has fluid at the bottom.
        Insects are attracted to the pitcher plant by a nectar around the rim of the pitcher opening;
        when an insect lands on the rim, it cannot maintain its balance on the slippery surface of the
        rim and falls into the opening and drowns in the fluid.
        <br/> 
            Bladderworts are water plants with traps on their leaves that resemble tiny bubbles. A
        small animal may swim by the plant, totally oblivious to the danger posed by the harmlesslooking
        bladderwort. If the small animal comes too close to the plant, the bubbles open
        without warning and the animal is pulled inside the plant and digested.
        <br/>
            Probably the best known of the carnivorous plants is the Venus flytrap. This plant
        features unusual leaf tips that look like an inviting place for an insect to rest and offers the
        enticement of promised food. If an unwary ladybug or dragonfly settles on the leaves of
        the Venus flytrap, the two leaves suddenly snap shut, trapping the insect and creating a
        delicious meal for the plant.
    </passage-text>
</passage>