<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>William Faulkner</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            Author William Faulkner is today recognized as one of America's greatest writers on
        the basis of a body of novels that so convincingly portray the culture of the South in the
        years following the Civil War, with its citizens overcome by grief and defeat and trying to
        cling to old values while struggling to take their place in a changing world. The acclaim that
        today is Faulkner's, however, was slow in coming.
        <br/>
            Though Faulkner was praised by some critics and reviewers during the first part of his
        career, his novels did not sell well and he was considered a fairly marginal author. For the
        first few decades of his career, he made his living writing magazine articles and working as a
        screenwriter rather than as a novelist. Throughout this period, he continued to write, though
        his novels, sometimes noted for the stirring portrait that they presented of life in the post-Civil
        War South, were generally relegated to the category of strictly regional writing and were
        not widely appreciated.
        <br/>
            Beginning in 1946, Faulkner's career took an unexpected and dramatic turn as
        Faulkner came to be recognized as considerably more than a regional writer. <i>The Portable 
        Faulkner</i> was published in that year by Viking Press; two years later he was elected to the
        prestigious National Academy of Arts and Letters; he was awarded the Nobel Prize for
        literature in 1949. Over the next decade, his work was recognized in various ways, including
        a National Book Award and two Pulitzer Prizes, and he became a novelist in residence at
        the University of Virginia. His success led to a degree of affluence that enabled him to take
        up the life of a southern gentleman, including horseback riding and fox hunting. Ironically, he
        died as a result of an accident related to these gentlemanly pursuits, succumbing as a result
        of injuries suffered during a fall from a horse.
    </passage-text>
</passage>