<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage scroll0='15' scroll='25'>
   <passage-text>
      <div align="center"><b>Continental Crust</b></div>
      <br/>The continental masses broadly consist of two basic subtypes, the active belts where mountains are created and inactive regions where older and more stable rock is found. The mountainous regions in the active belts grow through one of two very different geological processes, volcanism and tectonic activity. Volcanism is a process in which massive accumulations of volcanic rock are formed from the extrusion of magma, while tectonic activity occurs where massive crustal plates move and interact. However, the belts of recent mountain-making activity account for only a small percentage of the continental crust. The rest is made of comparatively inactive regions under which much older rock is found. Within these stable regions, there are two distinct types of crust: continental shields and mountain roots.<br/>
<i>Continental shields</i> are low-lying continental surfaces with complex arrangements of igneous and metamorphic rocks beneath. Continental shields may be either exposed or covered. The exposed shields contain very old rocks, often dating back to the early Precambrian age 2.5 to 4 billion years ago; today, they generally appear as low hills and plateaus that have been continuously eroded during their exposure. The Canadian Shield covers two-thirds of Canada and sweeps down into the midsection of the United States. Extensive exposed shields are also found in Scandinavia, South America, Africa, India, and Australia.<br/>
Areas where the continental shields have been covered by younger sedimentary layers are covered shields. These younger layers, which date from the Paleozoic to the Cenozoic eras, accumulated during periods when the shields subsided and were covered with water; during these periods, marine sediments were deposited in the ancient shield rocks in thicknesses of hundreds to thousands of meters. <exp>The shield areas</exp> then arched and <exp>became land surfaces again as the water <bg>receded</bg></exp>. Large sections of the sedimentary cover have worn down through erosion; however, the sedimentary coverage remains intact over vast areas today.<br/>
Inactive remains of older mountain belts are found in many places within the shields, and these inactive remnants of what were once towering mountains are called <i>mountain roots</i>. Many of what are today's mountain roots are formed of Paleozoic and early Mesozoic sedimentary rocks that have been reformed under intense pressure and, in many locations, have turned into metamorphic rocks such as slate and quartzite. Vast quantities of overlying rocks have eroded away from these remnants of tectonic ranges, and as a result only the lower parts of these geological structures remain. Mountain roots have the appearance of long and narrow ridges that rarely exceed 1,000 meters in height and belie the fact that these currently inactive ridges were formerly towering peaks.<br/>
Two important systems of mountain roots are the Caledonians and the Appalachians. The Caledonians formed during the Paleozoic Era, during a massive collision between two giant tectonic plates that occurred around 400 millions years ago. At their height, the Caledonians were extremely high alpine mountain chains, but since that time they have been eroding away to much lower mountains, hills, and plateaus. Today, the Caledonians form a belt of highlands across the maritime provinces of eastern Canada, several New England states in the United States, and northern parts of the British Isles and Scandinavia. The Appalachians formed during another massive collision of tectonic plates around 250 million years ago, near the end of the Paleozoic Era. This system of inactive mountain roots in North America, which today has a highest peak of only 6,684 feet, used to be extraordinarily high mountains rivaling today's Himalayas, which include the 29,028-foot Mount Everest.
 </passage-text>
</passage>
