<?xml version="1.0"?><passage scroll='19'>   <passage-text>      <div align="center"><b>Thermal Inertia</b></div>      <br/>Interactions between the atmosphere and the surface waters of the ocean dominate the earth's climate, and the main moderating influence of the ocean on our climate is due to its <b>thermal inertia</b>. This means that the temperature of the ocean tends to remain steady rather than fluctuating wildly; the waters of the ocean do not undergo the large seasonal swings in temperature that other substances do. Certain properties of water that contribute to the thermal inertia of the ocean are related to the concepts of (a) specific heat, (b) light penetration, (c) mixing, and (d) phase change.<br/>One factor that contributes to the thermal inertia of water is its <b><clk>specific heat</clk></b>. The specific heat of water is much greater than the specific heat of the materials that compose the earth's crust. A trip to the beach on a hot day should be enough to clarify this point. On a day with blistering sunshine, the sand will heat up much more than the water, and it is possible to burn the soles of one's feet on the sand while the water remains cool and refreshing.<br/>Another factor that contributes to the thermal inertia of the ocean is the relatively high degree of light penetration that occurs with water. Sunlight is able to penetrate several meters through ocean waters, a very different process from what takes place on land. <bg>Compared to <exp>land, where sunlight</exp> is concentrated at the surface and <exp>fails to penetrate deeply</exp>, <exp>sunlight penetrates through a much thicker layer of water</exp> in the ocean.</bg> Returning to the example of the sandy beach on a hot day, it is easy to notice that it is the surface of the sand that heats up so tremendously, while the sand only a few centimeters beneath the surface is much cooler because the sunlight has failed to penetrate very far beneath the surface. In the ocean water, there is not such a wide difference in temperature between the surface of the water and the water a few centimeters beneath the surface, at least in part because of the fact that sunlight penetrates more deeply through water than it does through sand.<br/>Mixing is a third factor that plays a role in the thermal inertia of the ocean. Wave action and turbulence cause the waters of the ocean to circulate, resulting in the distribution of heat from the sun throughout the water closer to the surface. As the cold waters from well below the surface intermix with the warmer waters closer to the surface, the surface waters are unable to heat up significantly. The fact that water mixes more easily than sand also helps to explain why the surface of the sand at the beach heats up considerably more than the surface of the water at the beach.<br/>Another mechanism that is extremely influential in moderating the temperature of the surface water of the ocean is phase change, which includes both changes between liquid and vapor phases at all latitudes and changes between liquid and solid phases at higher latitudes. These two types of phase change, evaporation and condensation at all latitudes and freezing and thawing at very high latitudes, each have the effect of contributing to thermal inertia.<br/>Evaporation and condensation of water make an essential contribution to thermal inertia at all latitudes. During hours of daylight, the removal of latent heat through evaporation tends to maintain the coolness of the surface of the water even when the sun is shining brightly. At night the process reverses, and moisture condenses; on land, moisture often condenses as dew, while over the ocean, moisture simply condenses back onto the surface of the ocean. This condensation releases the latent heat back onto the ocean, contributing to the maintenance of the warmth of the surface water. Overall, this means that evaporation of water during the heat of the day helps to maintain the surface coolness of the water, while condensation at night helps to maintain the warmth of the surface water.<br/>At higher latitudes, the freezing and melting also contribute to thermal inertia. In winter, latent heat is released as ice forms on the cooling surface of the water. The release of latent heat helps to prevent the remaining water from becoming colder. In summer, the process is reversed. The melting ice absorbs heat from the water and helps to keep it cool. In short, this means that the formation of ice helps to keep the water from becoming too cold, while the melting of ice helps to keep the water from becoming too hot. </passage-text> <clk-list> <clk-text>specific heat = the amount of heat energy that is needed to raise the temperature of 1 gram of a substance by 1 degree Celcius</clk-text> </clk-list></passage>