<?xml version="1.0"?><passage scroll0='bottom' scroll='43'>   <passage-text>      <div align="center"><b>Binet</b></div>      <br/>Alfred Binet (1857&#8211;1911) was a pioneer in the field of intelligence testing. Binet's work has had a major impact on modern education. Intelligence testing in the era before Binet was based upon the assumption that intelligence had a physiological basis. Physiologists knew that neural impulses took time to make their way through the nervous system, and it was believed by some that intelligence was determined by the speed of neural functioning and that, as a result, intelligence could be assessed by measuring physiological processes. Early intelligence tests thus consisted of measurements of physiological functions such as sensorimotor function, reaction time, and even  breathing capacity and muscular strength. However, by the end of the nineteenth century, psychologists realized that these physiological tests did not seem to do an adequate job in measuring intelligence; Alfred Binet was a leading proponent of the school of thought that believed that intelligence testing needed to concentrate not on physiological processes but on higher mental abilities.<br/>The basic tenet of Binet's work in the field of intelligence testing was that intelligence could be measured by assessing ten mental functions that he outlined: memory, imagery, imagination, attention, comprehension, suggestibility, aesthetic appreciation, moral sentiments, willpower, and motor skills. He considered these mental functions to be interactive rather than individual skills that serve as the foundation of mental ability, or intelligence.<br/>On behalf of the French Ministry of Education, Binet was charged with the task of developing a test to identify students in the educational system who were in need of special education. Binet, in collaboration with Th&#0233;ophile Simon, introduced a simple test in 1905 that assessed a child's ability to deal with items such as following a lighted candle and comparing two lines of slightly unequal length. The 1905 test was revised and expanded in 1908 and again in 1911 to include items classified by age levels extending from three to thirteen years. From this classification of items by age levels, the idea of <b>mental age</b> as a measurement of intelligence developed. A child's mental age was based upon his or her ability to complete the test items tied to a specific age level. Thus, an eight-year-old might be said to have a mental age of six if she or he was able to master the test items in the category for six-year-olds and might be said to have a mental age of ten if she or he was able to master the test items in the category for ten-year-olds.<br/>The Binet test moved into the U.S. educational system early in the twentieth century and underwent numerous revisions to ensure that the items on the test were appropriate for American school children. One major proponent of the use of this test was Lewis Terman of Stanford University, who in 1916 issued an Americanized version of the test that was developed at Stanford University and was known as the Stanford-Binet Intelligence Scale. This evaluative mechanism was quite similar to Binet's 1911 version of the test, with modifications to some of the items based upon tests conducted with children in the United States. <sqr/> The 1916 test was later replaced in 1937 by a more refined test that appeared in two different forms, <exp>the L form and the M form</exp>. <sqr/> Then, in 1960, the best items were selected from the two forms to create a single test, known as Form L-M of the Stanford-Binet. <sqr/> Further modifications were made to the test in the 1972 version, which was revised to reflect the disparate ethnic and socioeconomic backgrounds of students in American schools. <sqr/> <br/><br/><br/></passage-text></passage>