<?xml version="1.0"?><passage scroll='13'>   <passage-text>      <div align="center"><b>Hieroglyphics</b></div>      <br/>Hieroglyphics is a system of writing that was used by the ancient Egyptians for more than 3,000 years, until the A.D. 300s. The glory of the ancient Egyptian empire faded as a series of conquerors&#8212;the Persians, the Macedonians, and the Romans&#8212;invaded Egypt, and installed their leaders as non-Egyptian kings of Egypt. In the year 384 A.D., the Roman Emperor Theodosus issued a decree abolishing rites in the temples of Egypt, and this effectively put an end to the reading and writing of hieroglyphics. For the next 1,400 years, hieroglyphics remained on the monuments of ancient Egypt, but the ability to decode them was lost.<br/>In August, 1799, at the time of Napoleon's campaign in Egypt, a French officer found a fragment of a stone, with some finely engraved text on it, during work on fortifications close to an Egyptian town. The stone, which is now housed in the British Museum, has been named the Rosetta Stone. The significance of <exp>the Rosetta Stone</exp> is that it <exp>contains text in three types of writing: 14 lines of hieroglyphics, 32 of lines demotic</exp> (a simplified cursive form of hieroglyphics), <exp>and Greek</exp>. From the content of the Greek section, which was relatively easy to translate, it could be determined that the stone contained a message dating from 196 B.C. thanking King Ptolemy V for gifts and goodwill that he had bestowed upon the temples at Memphis. The hieroglyphics and demotics were untranslatable because the ability to understand hieroglyphics had been lost over the preceding 1,400 years. However, it was evident from the Rosetta Stone that the hieroglyphics indeed represented a system of writing.<br/>A first step in the decoding of the hieroglyphics was the understanding that oval frames throughout the hieroglyphics, known as cartouches or royal rings, were used in the hieroglyphics to highlight the names of kings, both the Egyptian and the non-Egyptian kings. A young historian and linguist, Jean-Fran&#0231;ois Champollion, was then able to decode the names of some of the non-Egyptian kings in the cartouches, which were written phonetically. Because Champollion was knowledgeable about the history of ancient Egypt and because the hieroglyphics of the non-Egyptian kings were written in phonetic hieroglyphics in which each hieroglyph represented a single consonant sound, Champollion was able to decode the hieroglyphs used in the cartouches that named the non-Egyptian rulers and determined which sounds each hieroglyph represented.<br/>After Champollion had decoded the phonetically written names of the non-Egyptian rulers in the hieroglyphs, it became clear that all of the hieroglyphics could not be decoded simply by matching a hieroglyph to a sound. Champollion's amazing breakthrough in decoding the remaining hieroglyphs was the discovery that, while some of the hieroglyphs did indeed each represent a single sound, others represented groups of sounds, and still others were pictographs representing concepts; a factor that made some of the hieroglyphics difficult to decode was that these three different types of hieroglyphs could be used together in a single word. The names of the non-Egyptian kings were written only with hieroglyphs representing single sounds, which made them the easiest to decode first, while the names of the Egyptian kings could be written in an amalgamation of all three types of hieroglyphs. The decoding of the hieroglyphics that referred to the Egyptian king Ramses indicated how the three types of hieroglyphics could be combined into one word. The name Ramses consisted of three hieroglyphs: the first was a pictograph of the sun, Ra; the second was a hieroglyph representing the two consonants <i>M</i> and <i>S</i>; and the third was a hieroglyph representing the single consonant <i>S</i>.<br/> </passage-text></passage>