<?xml version="1.0"?><passage scroll0='bottom' scroll='57'>   <passage-text>      <div align="center"><b>History of Business</b></div>      <br/>Businesses have not always existed in their current form; instead, they have evolved slowly from simple enterprises and bartering arrangements into the giant conglomerates and multinational corporations of today's world. The development of modern business has its roots in the agrarian society of the medieval world, in the early trading enterprises that came about as a natural result of the worldwide exploratory expeditions of the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries, in the colonial expansion that ensued, and in the myriad changes that occurred in business surrounding the Industrial Revolution that began in the nineteenth century.<br/>In the typical agrarian societies of the thirteenth to sixteenth centuries, business was limited mainly to local trade. The manorial system that was in place during this period meant that a high percentage of the population was involved in agriculture. The hereditary owner of the manor would lease land to the peasantry and would receive agricultural services or products as payment. Each manor tended to be a self-sufficient unit, with little dependence on outside trade. Among the members of the population of the manor, business tended to be conducted only on a small scale and consisted mainly of bartering of goods and services in the local marketplace.<br/>The scope of business began expanding considerably outside of the local marketplace as exploration of the world expanded. A new type of business, charter companies, came about during this era. Such companies were granted charters by governments, often with monopolistic trade rights for specific products, such as cloth or tea, in specific geographical areas. A charter company was an association of merchants, each of whom traded individually but was subject to a rigid set of rules outlined in a charter agreement that governed all facets of the business, including prices, volumes, profits, and procedures for conducting business.<br/>Business continued to develop during the colonial era as colonialism reinforced the charter companies and also gave rise to forms of business known as  joint-stock companies and limited partnerships. Charter companies often played a role in colonialism: the London Company, the Plymouth Bay Company, and the Massachusetts Bay Company were directly involved in the settlement of colonists in North America. Charter companies, however, were quite a risky form of business in that it was possible to lose one hundred percent of one's investment easily. In order to limit the risk, many charter companies began operating on a joint-stock basis; members of the charter borrowed money from investors to finance a particular project and agreed to share profits from the venture with the investors in return. A major problem with joint-stock companies, however, was related to the liability of all investors for any losses incurred by a particular venture. A new form of business, the limited partnership, came about as investors became wary of investing in joint ventures because of their liability. In a limited partnership, the amount of liability of investors was not as great, and more investors were eager to provide capital for ventures that limited the liability of the investors.<br/>As the world moved into the nineteenth century, <exp>numerous changes were taking place <bg>that</bg> greatly influenced the way in which business was conducted</exp> in an era referred to as the Industrial Revolution. The entrepreneurial spirit was flourishing, and a system of finance was developing to include the loans and extensions of credit that enabled small businesses to develop into larger ones. A large class of wage-earning labor was emerging as the manorial system broke up and workers moved from rural to urban areas, and the factory system, with its emphasis on efficiency of labor through the specialization and simplification of tasks, was inaugurated. These factors all played a part in the development of the modern system of corporations of today. </passage-text></passage>