<?xml version="1.0"?><passage scroll='45'>   <passage-text>      <div align="center"><b>Jane Addams</b></div>      <br/>Social reformer Jane Addams (1860&#8211;1935) achieved fame as the founder of Hull House, a settlement house in Chicago, Illinois, that provided much-needed services to the poorest and neediest residents of the area. She also capitalized on the recognition and acclaim for her efforts at Hull House by actively voicing her views on the issues of the day.<br/>Jane Addams was born into a family of privilege. Her father was a successful businessman in their hometown of Cedarville, Illinois, and her family was the wealthiest and most prominent in the small town. Jane was raised in a loving environment with all of the advantages of the position that her family held. Her father encouraged her education, something unusual for the time, and after high school she continued on with her studies. She had wanted to attend recently opened Smith College, an institution of higher learning for women, with a curriculum that was modeled after the rigorous instruction at exclusive men's institutions such as Harvard or Yale; however, her father insisted that she stay closer to home and sent her to Rockford Academy, a conservative institution dedicated to turning out proper young ladies ready to take appropriate roles in society.  During her stay at Rockford Academy, she began to rebel, using her position as a writer on the college magazine to address issues of societal reform rather than the lighter topics usually found in the college paper. After finishing at Rockford, she fell ill. She decided to travel to Europe in the hope that a change of scenery would help her condition to improve.<br/>While on the European trip, Jane Addams did much more than visit the vacation destinations of the wealthy class in that she wanted to get to know Europe on a very different level. She toured the slums of England and witnessed firsthand the negative results of industrialization, and this visit had a profound effect on her desire to work to bring about change in the world. After returning home, where she was expected to take on a role as kindly maiden aunt who would assist in the upbringing of her nieces and nephews, she made a momentous decision to turn her life in a different direction.<br/>She had stayed in contact with a friend from college, Ellen Starr, who was teaching school in Chicago. They both felt strongly about the need to do something to help the poorest residents of the city, whom they considered victims of the Industrial Revolution. Together they came up with a plan to develop an institution that could provide assistance and services to society's neediest members. In spite of strong objections from her family, Jane Addams moved to Chicago and, with Ellen Starr, began developing their plan.<br/>Within a few months of her arrival in Chicago, Addams was able to raise enough, through her contacts with church members and members of her social class, to open Hull House. Opened in 1889, Hull House, in a slum area of Chicago, was a rundown mansion that was converted to a service organization for the needy population. Programs were created to provide food and housing and medical care for the working poor and newly arrived unemployed immigrants. Over time, <exp>Hull House grew substantially, financed solely by private funds</exp>; it eventually included a total of 13 buildings and offered wide-ranging services such as nursery care, recreational activities, adult education courses, a music school, and art workshops, in addition to the core social services.<br/>In spite of all the good work accomplished at Hull House, Jane Addams was not always viewed as a positive influence. She was an outspoken proponent of women's rights and lived a life that demonstrated that a woman could have a substantive role outside the home, a position that was assured of arousing conflict in many parts of society. Furthermore, she strongly advocated peace over war, a position that also made her unpopular. She gave numerous lectures on the topic of peace at college campuses and took part in the development of organizations devoted to peace: she was instrumental in the formation of the Women's Peace Party and the Women's International League for Peace. When the United States entered World War I in 1917, Addams was publicly vilified for her unpopular position against the war. The negative publicity affected her ability to raise money, yet she continued to write, lecture, and present her views on pacifism and on the need to improve social conditions and the role of women in society. Despite the negative opinions her positions sometimes aroused, she was regarded as a role model by many women during her lifetime and since her death in 1935 has come to be regarded as a voice of social conscience. </passage-text></passage>