<?xml version='1.0'?>
<question-list type='read' passage-file='ASR07P0.xml'>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P1.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>It is indicated in paragraph 2 that cocoa trees are native to</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>South America</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>Mexico</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Spain</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Central America</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>cocoa trees are indigenous to South America's river valleys</exp>. This means that cocoa trees are native to <exp>South America</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P2.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>It is mentioned in paragraph 2 that all of the following were involved in the cultivation of cocoa trees by the seventh century EXCEPT</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>the Mayans</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>the Aztecs</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>the Toltecs</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>the Spanish</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>by the seventh century, the Mayans had brought the trees north into Mexico, and numerous other cultures including the Aztecs and the Toltecs seem to have been involved in the production of cocoa trees</exp>. This means that <exp>the Mayans</exp> in the first answer, <exp>the Aztecs</exp> in the second answer, and <exp>the Toltecs</exp> in the third answer were involved in the cultivation of cocoa trees. All of the answers EXCEPT the last one are mentioned in paragraph 2. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>  
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P3.xml" skills="6">
      <question-text>It is NOT stated in paragraph 2 that <i>cacahuatl</i> was</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>used as a currency</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>a special drink</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>rather spicy</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>rather bitter</exp></answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>a special drink, <i>cacahuatl</i>, which was made&#8230;with red pepper</exp> and states that <exp>it was so bitter</exp>. This means that <i>cacahuatl</i> was <exp>a special drink</exp> in paragraph 2, <exp>rather spicy</exp> in the third answer, and <exp>rather bitter</exp> in the last answer. The first answer is the one that is NOT stated and is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P4.xml" skills="6">
      <question-text>What is NOT listed in paragraph 3 as an ingredient in the paste developed by the Spanish?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>A sweetener</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>Spices</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>Nuts</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>Orange peel</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>they created a paste by heating a mixture of ground sugar, cinnamon, cloves, anise, almonds, hazelnuts, vanilla, dried cocoa beans, and orange-flavored water</exp>. The ground sugar is <exp>a sweetener</exp> in the first answer; the cinnamon, cloves, and anise are <exp>spices</exp> in the second answer; and almonds and hazelnuts are <exp>nuts</exp> in the third answer. The last answer is the one that is NOT listed and is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>  
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P5.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>It is indicated in paragraph 3 that <i>chocolatl</i></question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>contained plantain leaves</answer-text>
         <answer-text>was a slab of hardened paste</answer-text>
         <answer-text>was cut into pieces</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>was a  hot beverage</exp></answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>they prepared a drink, which they called <i>chocolatl</i>, by dissolving pieces of the hardened paste into hot water or broth</exp>. This means that <i>chocolatl</i> <exp>was a hot beverage</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P6.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>It is stated in paragraph 4 that</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>chocolate appeared in England before it appeared in Spain</answer-text>
         <answer-text>chocolate candies were quite popular in London in the 1600s</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>coffeehouses were popular in London before chocolate houses were</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>by the sixteenth century it was popular to dissolve chocolate in milk</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>chocolate houses, which were fashionable versions of the coffeehouses that had sprung up in London in the 1600s.</exp> From this, it can be determined that <exp>coffeehouses were popular in London before chocolate houses were.</exp> The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P7.xml" skills="6">
      <question-text>According to paragraph 5, it is NOT true that van Houten's invention was used to</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>press cocoa beans</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>mix cocoa butter and cocoa beans</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>separate cocoa powder from cocoa beans</answer-text>
         <answer-text>remove cocoa butter from cocoa beans</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>2</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>Conrad van Houten invented a press that would squeeze much of the cocoa butter out of cocoa beans</exp>. This means that it is NOT true that van Houten's invention was used to <exp>mix cocoa butter and cocoa beans</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P8.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>Which of the following is true, according to paragraph 5?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>It was easier to blend cocoa powder with sugar than it was to blend cocoa butter with sugar.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Better candies could be prepared using cocoa powder rather than cocoa butter.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Adding cocoa butter to drinks made the drinks smoother and tastier.</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>Better drinks could be prepared using cocoa powder rather than cocoa butter.</exp></answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>it was possible to create a much smoother and tastier drink by blending cocoa powder without the cocoa butter into hot liquids</exp>. This means that <exp>better drinks could be prepared using cocoa powder rather than cocoa butter</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P9.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>What 1870s innovation by Swiss candy makers is discussed in paragraph 5?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>The creation of solid chocolate</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>The addition of dried milk to chocolate</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>The use of paste in the production of chocolate</answer-text>
         <answer-text>The addition of whole milk to chocolate</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>2</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>in the 1870s, Swiss candy makers improved chocolate production by adding the dried milk&#8230;to chocolate to make solid milk chocolate</exp>. This means that the 1870s innovation by Swiss candy makers discussed in paragraph 5 is <exp>the addition of dried milk to chocolate</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P10.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>According to paragraph 6, what factor limited the widespread enjoyment of chocolate in the period before the end of the nineteenth century?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>Its bitter taste</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Its use of dried milk</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>Its high price</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>Its use of cocoa butter</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>by the end of the nineteenth century, chocolate&#8230;was not widely enjoyed because of its prohibitive price</exp>. This means that the factor that limited the widespread enjoyment of chocolate in the period before the end of the nineteenth century was <exp>its high price</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P11.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>According to paragraph 6, Hershey's caramel company</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>was not located in Hershey</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>created caramels using dried milk</answer-text>
         <answer-text>produced caramel-covered chocolates</answer-text>
         <answer-text>eventually went bankrupt</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>Hershey was operating the successful Lancaster Caramel Company</exp>. This means that Hershey's caramel company <exp>was not located in Hershey</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P12.xml" skills="6">
      <question-text>It is NOT mentioned in paragraph 6 that Hershey wanted to</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>mass-produce chocolate</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>sell chocolate in individual servings</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>create an exclusive brand of chocolate</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>make his chocolate available at a low price</exp></answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>he also decided to use mass production techniques to create large quantities of individually wrapped and affordable chocolates for the public</exp>. This means that Hershey wanted to <exp>mass-produce chocolate</exp> in the first answer, to <exp>sell chocolate in individual servings</exp> in the second answer, and to <exp>make his chocolate available at a low price</exp> in the last answer. The third answer is the one that is NOT mentioned and is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>      
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR07P13.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>Which of the following is true, according to paragraph 6?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>Hershey built his new chocolate factory in Lancaster.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>The original "Hershey Bar" was first produced in Hershey, Pennsylvania.</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>The name of the town where the new factory was located changed its name.</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>The new factory in Hershey produced caramels as well as chocolates.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>he began building a new factory in Derry Church, Pennsylvania</exp> and that <exp>by 1906 the community had been renamed Hershey</exp>. This means that <exp>the name of the town where the new factory was located changed its name</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>                       
</question-list>
