<?xml version='1.0'?>
<question-list type='read' passage-file='ASR13P0.xml'>
<question type='select.1' passage-file='ASR13P1.xml' skills='9'>
<direction-text>Select the appropriate sentences from the answer choices that are key points in a discussion of <exp>how well various publishers succeeded in creating adless newspapers</exp>. <i><b>This question is worth 3 points.</b></i></direction-text>
<intro-text><b>How well various publishers succeeded in creating adless newspapers</b></intro-text>
<answer-list>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Scripps managed to establish two newspapers without ads, though neither endured</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>Scripps' adless paper in Chicago was the <i>Chicago Day Book</i></exp>, that <exp>it was actually profitable for only one month</exp>, and that <exp>publication of the <i>Chicago Day Book</i> was stopped in 1917</exp>. The passage goes on to state that <exp>he opened a second adless paper, the <i>Philadelphia News-Post</i></exp> and that <exp>this paper was operated without any advertising for a two-year period from 1912 to 1914 before losses forced its closing</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>Scripps managed to establish two newspapers without ads, though neither endured</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>how well various publishers succeeded in creating adless newspapers</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Dana managed to meet his objective of eliminating advertising from the</exp> <expi>New York Sun,</expi> <exp>though only for a short period of time</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>Dana</exp> and states that <exp>he made the elimination of advertising from the <i>New York Sun</i> a primary objective</exp> and that <exp>he was unable to achieve the goal of publishing a newspaper without any reliance on advertising</exp>. This means that it is NOT true that <exp>Dana managed to meet his objective of eliminating advertising from the <i>New York Sun</i>, though only for a short period of time</exp>. This answer is therefore not a correct answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Ingersoll created an adless paper that was initially immensely successful but then tumbled</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>Ingersoll</exp> and states that <exp>he hoped to create a high-quality paper&#8230;unencumbered with advertising</exp>, that <exp>first-day sales were an incredible 450,000 copies</exp>, and that <exp>within three months, the paper had lost so much money that Ingersoll and his investors were forced to sell out</exp>. This means that <exp>Ingersoll created an adless paper that was initially immensely successful but then tumbled</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>how well various publishers succeeded in creating adless newspapers</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Scripps proved quite successful in creating a business empire based on the penny press.</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>Scripps had first achieved success in publishing by creating an empire in the penny press</exp>. This means that it is true that <exp>Scripps proved quite successful in creating a business empire based on the penny press</exp>. However, even though this is true, it is not a critical point in supporting the topic of <exp><b>how well various publishers succeeded in creating adless newspapers</b></exp>. This answer is therefore not a correct answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Dana managed to reduce, but not eliminate, the role of advertising in the newspaper that he owned.</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>Dana</exp> and states that <exp>he did reduce the paper's dependence on advertising and relegated the wishes of advertisers to a secondary position behind the news</exp>. This means that <exp>Dana managed to reduce, but not eliminate, the role of advertising in the newspaper that he owned</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>how well various publishers succeeded in creating adless newspapers</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Scripps managed to keep an adless paper going in New York City for a short period of time.</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>Scripps</exp> and states that <exp>he began planning his opening venture in New York City; however, his plans for an adless paper in New York City fell apart before the first paper was printed</exp>. This means that it is NOT true that <exp>Scripps managed to keep an adless paper going in New York City for a short period of time</exp>. This answer is therefore not a correct answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
</answer-list>
<key>0.1.2.</key>
</question>
</question-list>

