<?xml version='1.0'?>
<question-list type='read' passage-file='ASR11P0.xml'>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P1.xml" skills="7">
      <question-text>It can be inferred from paragraph 1 that, prior to November 2, 1920,</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>the results of the presidential election were actually known</answer-text>
         <answer-text>other commercial radio broadcasts took place</answer-text>
         <answer-text>KDKA was a successful commercial venture</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>there may have been amateur broadcasts</exp></answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>the broadcast on November 2, 1920&#8230;is generally considered the first commercial U.S. radio broadcast</exp> and mentions <exp>wide-ranging efforts in the field of wireless communication in the decades that preceded it</exp>. It can be inferred from this that <exp>there may have been amateur broadcasts</exp> prior to November 2, 1920. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P2.xml" skills="7">
      <question-text>It can be inferred from paragraph 2 that, prior to the 1870s,</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>Maxwell had already conceived the idea for radios</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>radios did not exist</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>only very basic radios were in use</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Marconi was working on developing a radio</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>2</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>the initial concept of wireless communication came about in 1873</exp>. It can be inferred from this that, prior to the 1870s, <exp>radios did not exist</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P3.xml" skills="8">
      <question-text>The author mentions <bg>these initial stages</bg> in paragraph 3 in order to</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>initiate a discussion of traditional wired forms of communication</answer-text>
         <answer-text>describe an era when wireless communication would have broad-ranging uses</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>relate the ideas in paragraph 3 to those that were presented in paragraph 2</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>introduce a discussion of wireless communication after World War I</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The first sentence of paragraph 2 mentions <exp>the initial concept</exp>, and the first sentence of paragraph 3 mentions <exp>these initial stages</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the author mentions <exp>these initial stages</exp> in paragraph 3 to <exp>relate the ideas in paragraph 3 to those that were presented in paragraph 2</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P4.xml" skills="7">
      <question-text>Based on the information in paragraph 3, it can be determined that the military was most likely interested in wireless communication because</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>field units were unable to communicate by means of traditional wired forms of communication</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>the military was greatly involved with private shipping</answer-text>
         <answer-text>the controversy and competition could be controlled by the military</answer-text>
         <answer-text>the military wanted to use wireless communication to broadcast information</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>wireless communication&#8230;quickly caught the interest of the military, which recognized the potential that it provided for communication among rapidly moving military units</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the military was most likely interested in wireless communication because <exp>field units were unable to communicate by means of traditional wired forms of communication</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P5.xml" skills="8">
      <question-text>Why does the author mention <bg>World War I</bg> in paragraph 3?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>It provides one example of the many uses of commercial radio at the time.</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>It represents a point at which a critical change in the development of commercial radio broadcasting occurred.</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>It demonstrates how the failure to cooperate led to controversy.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>It describes a period when traditional wired forms of communication first came into use.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>2</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>in the period preceding World War I, there was a considerable amount of controversy and competition among those seeking to garner patents and create business empires using wireless communication</exp> and that <exp>the cooperation among entrepreneurs in the field of wireless communication that resulted from the war effort led to a sense of cooperation following the war that was beneficial in the further development of the radio industry</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the author mentions <exp>World War I</exp> because <exp>it represents a point at which a critical change in the development of commercial radio broadcasting occurred</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P6.xml" skills="8">
      <question-text>The author mentions <bg>the major players in the field</bg> in paragraph 4 in order to show that the organizations involved in radio communication</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>thought that radios would be used primarily for games</answer-text>
         <answer-text>would be able to reach an agreement</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>were taking part in a competitive way</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>were interested in broadcasting sports</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>a short-lived agreement was reached by the major players in the field</exp> and that <exp>according to the terms of this agreement, American Telephone and Telegraph Company (AT&amp;T) would manufacture radio transmitters, General Electric (GE) and Westinghouse would manufacture radio receivers</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the author mentions <exp>the major players in the field</exp> in order to show that the organizations involved in radio communication <exp>were taking part in a competitive way</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P7.xml" skills="7">
      <question-text>It is implied in paragraph 4 that the 1920 agreement did not last for long because it was based on the idea that</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>radios were to be used to communicate only between one sender and one receiver</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>radio broadcasting needed to be implemented as soon as possible</answer-text>
         <answer-text>only three companies should be involved in radio broadcasting</answer-text>
         <answer-text>radio broadcasting was far more important than individual transmitting and receiving</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>this agreement, however, was in existence for only a short time because it failed to take into account a new use for radio, that of radio broadcasting</exp>. This implies that the 1920 agreement did not last for long because it was based on the idea that <exp>radios were to be used to communicate only between one sender and one receiver</exp> rather than to broadcast from one sender to many receivers. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P8.xml" skills="8">
      <question-text>Why does the author mention the <bg>"mixing bowl"</bg> in paragraph 4?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>To indicate that AT&amp;T, GE, and Westinghouse had merged into one company</answer-text>
         <answer-text>To indicate that one of the products sold by RCA would be mixing bowls</answer-text>
         <answer-text>To indicate that the information shared by the three companies was rather confusing</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>To create a mental image that RCA represented the combined interests of its three parent companies</exp></answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>the Radio Corporation of America (RCA), which was jointly owned by AT&amp;T, Westinghouse, and GE, would serve as the "mixing bowl" for the products and information for the three companies</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the author mentions the <exp>"mixing bowl"</exp> in order <exp>to create a mental image that RCA represented the combined interests of its three parent companies</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>      
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P9.xml" skills="7">
      <question-text>It is implied in paragraph 5 that the earliest conception of radio communication was</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>a single sender communicating with a single receiver</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>a single sender communicating with multiple receivers</answer-text>
         <answer-text>multiple senders communicating with a single receiver</answer-text>
         <answer-text>multiple senders communicating with multiple receivers</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>this agreement, however, was in existence for only a short time because it failed to take into account a new use for radio, that of radio broadcasting</exp> and that <exp>the conception of radio communication changed from one of communication between a single sender and a single receiver to one of broadcasting to numerous receivers</exp>. It is implied in this that the earliest conception of radio communication was <exp>a single sender communicating with a single receiver</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR11P10.xml" skills="8">
      <question-text>The author mentions <bg>a Pittsburgh department store</bg> in paragraph 5 in order to show that the development of commercial radio broadcasting was enabled because broadcasting</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>could take place in department stores</answer-text>
         <answer-text>required receivers to be installed at stores</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>offered opportunities to other commercial ventures</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>could be promoted during sales at stores</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>KDKA was started as an amateur operation by Frank Conrad</exp>, that <exp>his broadcasts&#8230;increased in popularity when a Pittsburgh department store began promoting Conrad's broadcasts by selling radio receivers to pick up the broadcasts</exp>, that <exp>Westinghouse&#8230;began promoting the sales of its own receivers</exp>, and that <exp>Westinghouse filed an application for a commercial license for KDKA</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the author mentions <exp>a Pittsburgh department store</exp> in order to show that the development of radio broadcasting was enabled because it <exp>offered opportunities to other commercial ventures</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>                                                
</question-list>   
