<?xml version='1.0'?>
<question-list type='read' passage-file='ASR14P0.xml'>
<question type='select.2' passage-file='ASR14P1.xml' skills='10'>
<direction-text>Select the appropriate phrases from the answer choices and match them to the type of aphasia to which they relate. TWO of the answer choices will NOT be used. <i><b>This question is worth 3 points.</b></i></direction-text>
<key>3.014.25</key>
<category-list>
<category>
<category-text><b><exp>Agrammatism</exp></b></category-text>
</category>
<category>
<category-text><b><exp>Fluent aphasia</exp></b></category-text>
</category>
</category-list>
<answer-list>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Often makes it difficult for a sufferer to understand others</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>a person who suffers from fluent aphasia&#8230;tends not to understand what others are saying</exp>. This means that fluent aphasia <exp>often makes it difficult for a sufferer to understand others</exp>. This answer should therefore be used to describe <exp><b>fluent aphasia</b></exp>.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Is used in a different way from its literal meaning of "without speech"</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>though aphasia literally means "without speech," it is often used in reference to the disorder suffered by people whose speech is problematic</exp>. The answer choice <exp>is used in a different way from its literal meaning of "without speech"</exp> is true information from the passage, but it is information that is not critical to the differentiation between <exp><b>agrammatism</b></exp> and <exp><b>fluent aphasia</b></exp>, so this is not a correct answer choice.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Can result from damage to an area of the brain in front of and above the left ear</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>Paul Broca indicated an area in the brain in front of and slightly above the left ear&#8230;that damage to this general region of the brain is likely to result in severe speech problems; as a result, agrammatic speech is sometimes known as Broca's aphasia</exp>. From this, it can be determined that agrammatism <exp>can result from damage to an area of the brain in front of and above the left ear</exp>. This answer should therefore be used to describe <exp><b>agrammatism</b></exp>.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Makes it difficult for someone to speak fluently</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp><b>agrammatism</b> is the technical term for one type of aphasic condition in which people have difficulty stringing words together into sentences</exp>. This means that agrammatism <exp>makes it difficult for someone to speak fluently</exp>. This answer should therefore be used to describe <exp><b>agrammatism</b></exp>.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Does not generally inhibit the ability to speak fluently</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>a person who suffers from fluent aphasia can speak quite fluently</exp>. This means that fluent aphasia <exp>does not generally inhibit the ability to speak fluently</exp>. This answer should therefore be used to describe <exp><b>fluent aphasia</b></exp>.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Always results from damage to the left side of the brain</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>it is not always the case that brain damage to a particular spot in the brain automatically results in a particular speech disorder</exp>. This means that it is NOT true that either agrammatism or fluent aphasia <exp>always results from damage to the left side of the brain</exp>, so this is not a correct answer choice.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Does not generally inhibit understanding of others</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>agrammatism</exp> and states that <exp>someone with this condition can generally understand what others say quite well</exp>. This means agrammatism <exp>does not generally inhibit understanding of others</exp>.  This answer should therefore be used to describe <exp><b>agrammatism</b></exp>.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Can result from damage to an area in the back of the brain and under the left ear</exp></answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>a number of patients who suffered from fluent aphasia had severe brain damage toward the back of the brain, in an area under the left ear</exp>. This means that fluent aphasia <exp>can result from damage to an area in the back of the brain and under the left ear</exp>. This answer should therefore be used to describe <exp><b>fluent aphasia</b></exp>.
</explain-text>
</answer>
</answer-list>
</question>
</question-list>

