<?xml version='1.0'?>
<question-list type='read' passage-file='ASR15P0.xml'>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P1.xml" skills="6">
      <question-text>Which of the following is NOT true according to paragraph 1?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>Galaxies may contain billions of stars.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>On the average, the distance between galaxies is around 20 times the diameter of a galaxy.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>It is unusual for stars to collide.</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>The average distance between stars is 70 times their diameter</exp>.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>the average distance between stars is astronomical, perhaps 10,000,000 times their diameter</exp>. From this, it can be determined that it is NOT true that <exp>the average distance between stars is 70 times their diameter</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P2.xml" skills="8">
      <question-text>The author mentions <bg>tails and bridges</bg> in paragraph 2 in order to</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>provide a visual image of the parts of galaxies that have been affected by gravitational forces</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>provide examples of the types of galaxies that tend to collide</answer-text>
         <answer-text>describe the recognizable characteristics of the colliding galaxies called the Mice</answer-text>
         <answer-text>create a visual roadmap of the routes that galaxies take through the skies</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>the two galaxies pass through each other, and the gravitational forces in the two galaxies alter the shapes of the galaxies, often producing tails and bridges</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the author mentions <exp>tails and bridges</exp> in order to <exp>provide a visual image of the parts of galaxies that have been affected by gravitational forces</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P3.xml" skills="2">
      <question-text>The word <bg>its</bg> in paragraph 2 refers to</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>a mouse</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>the Whirlpool galaxy</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>a smaller galaxy</answer-text>
         <answer-text>a bridge</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>2</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>the Whirlpool galaxy appears to be connected to a smaller galaxy by means of&#8230;one of its long spirals</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that the word <exp>its</exp> refers to <exp>the Whirlpool galaxy</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P4.xml" skills="1">
      <question-text>The word <bg>last</bg> in paragraph 2 could best be replaced by</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>end in</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>endure for</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>finish with</answer-text>
         <answer-text>lose out to</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>2</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>the interactions between galaxies last hundreds of millions of years</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>last</exp> could best be replaced by the phrase <exp>endure for</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P5.xml" skills="1">
      <question-text>The word <bg>merge</bg> in paragraph 3 is closest in meaning to</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>divide</answer-text>
         <answer-text>swallow</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>join</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>appear</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>two galaxies</exp> and states that <exp>they eventually merge into a single galaxy</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that <exp>merge</exp> is closest in meaning to <exp>join</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>    
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P6.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>What occurs during galactic cannibalism, according to paragraph 3?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>A larger galaxy is absorbed by a smaller one.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>The first step involves pulling at the core of the smaller galaxy.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>The outer stars of the smaller galaxy are absorbed by its core.</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>The core of the smaller galaxy generally manages to remain visible</exp>.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>while the process of galactic cannibalism is taking place&#8230;the cores of both the larger galaxy and the smaller galaxy can be clearly visible</exp>. This means that during galactic cannibalism, <exp>the core of the smaller galaxy generally manages to remain visible</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type='insert' passage-file='ASR15P7.xml' skills='4'>
<insert-text><b>Instead, they may follow <exp>one of two scenarios</exp>.</b></insert-text>
<key>1</key>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>in certain situations, when two galaxies collide, they do not always pass through each other</exp> and later mentions <exp>one situation</exp> and <exp>another situation</exp>. A sentence mentioning <exp>one of two scenarios</exp> would logically come between these ideas. The first square in paragraph 3 is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P8.xml" skills="3">
      <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 4?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>Astronomers have recently found some giant galaxies that have cannibalized a number of galaxies.</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>Astronomers used to think that certain giant galaxies that appeared to have a number of nuclei were galactic cannibals</exp>.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>When astronomers find galaxies with multiple nuclei, they know that they have found galactic cannibals.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Even though a galaxy has multiple nuclei, it is not certain whether or not the galaxy is a galactic cannibal.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>2</key>
      <explain-text>
The highlighted sentence mentions <exp>some giant elliptical galaxies, with what appear to be multiple nuclei</exp>, which means <exp>certain giant galaxies that appeared to have a number of nuclei</exp>, and states that <exp>astronomers once thought that these giant galaxies were giant galactic cannibals</exp>, which means that <exp>astronomers used to think that</exp>&#8230;they&#8230;<exp>were galactic cannibals</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P9.xml" skills="1">
      <question-text>The phrase <bg>put forth</bg> in paragraph 4 is closest in meaning to</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>encounter</answer-text>
         <answer-text>understand</answer-text>
         <answer-text>deny</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>promote</exp></answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>one such galaxy&#8230;was used to put forth the hypothesis</exp>. From this context, it can be determined that the phrase <exp>put forth</exp> is closest in meaning to <exp>promote</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
 </question>   
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P10.xml" skills="8">
      <question-text>Why does the author mention <bg>voracious monsters</bg> in paragraph 4?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>To emphasize how violently the galaxies strike each other</answer-text>
         <answer-text>To emphasize how much energy the giant galaxies consume</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>To emphasize how many smaller galaxies the giant galaxies seem to consume</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>To emphasize how really big the giant galaxies are</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>the hypothesis that galaxies could be voracious monsters, capable of swallowing up uncountable other galaxies simultaneously</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the author mentions <exp>voracious monsters</exp> in order <exp>to emphasize how many smaller galaxies the giant galaxies seem to consume</exp>. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
 </question>       
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P11.xml" skills="5">
      <question-text>It is stated in paragraph 4 that scientists today are quite certain that</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>galactic cannibalism does not really exist</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>there is a limited amount of galactic cannibalism</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>galactic cannibalism is commonplace</answer-text>
         <answer-text>galactic cannibals are capable of taking over numerous small galaxies at the same time</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>2</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>astronomers are now confident that galactic cannibalism exists among a limited number of interacting galaxies</exp>. This means that scientists are quite certain that <exp>there is a limited amount of galactic cannibalism</exp>. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
 </question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR15P12.xml" skills="7">
      <question-text>Based on the information in paragraph 5, what will most likely happen to the Magellanic Clouds in the distant future?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>They will become galactic cannibals.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>They will develop separate nuclei.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>They will become regular galaxies.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>They will <exp>become part of the Milky Way</exp>.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>our own galaxy, the Milky Way</exp> and states that <exp>our galaxy is beginning to digest the Magellanic Clouds.</exp>  From this, it can be determined that the Magellanic Clouds will most likely <exp>become part of the Milky Way</exp> in the distant future.The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
 </question>           
<question type='select.1' passage-file='ASR15P13.xml' skills='9'>
<direction-text>Select the appropriate sentences from the answer choices that are key points in a discussion of <exp>what occurs when galaxies cross paths</exp>. THREE of the answer choices will NOT be used. <i><b>This question is worth 3 points.</b></i></direction-text>
<intro-text><b>What occurs when galaxies cross paths</b></intro-text>
<answer-list>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>A larger galaxy may cannibalize a smaller galaxy</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>if a much larger galaxy comes into contact with a smaller galaxy, the larger galaxy may absorb the smaller one</exp>. This means that <exp>a larger galaxy may cannibalize a smaller galaxy</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>what occurs when galaxies cross paths</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Tails and bridges will develop on galaxies that have merged</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>two galaxies pass through each other,&#8230;often producing tails and bridges</exp>. This means that tails and bridges develop as galaxies pass through each other, but it is NOT stated that <exp>tails and bridges will develop on galaxies that have merged</exp>. This answer is therefore not a correct answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Two galaxies passing through each other may have an effect on each other's shape</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>galaxies that appear to be colliding</exp> and states that <exp>the two galaxies pass through each other, and the gravitational forces in the two galaxies alter the shapes of the galaxies</exp>. This means that <exp>two galaxies passing through each other may have an effect on each other's shape</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>what occurs when galaxies cross paths</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>The nucleus of the larger galaxy may divide into numerous nuclei</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>galaxies, with what appear to be multiple nuclei</exp> and states that <exp>astronomers once thought that these giant galaxies were giant galactic cannibals that had consumed many smaller galaxies</exp>. However, it is NOT stated in the passage that <exp>the nucleus of the larger galaxy may divide into numerous nuclei</exp>. This answer is therefore not a correct answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>A large galaxy will most likely cannibalize numerous smaller galaxies simultaneously</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>astronomers are not convinced of the existence of cannibalistic galactic monsters that swallow up large numbers of smaller galaxies simultaneously</exp>. This means astronomers are NOT convinced that it is true that <exp>a large galaxy will most likely cannibalize numerous smaller galaxies simultaneously</exp>. This answer is therefore not a correct answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
<answer>
<answer-text><exp>Two galaxies that cross paths may merge into one larger galaxy</exp>.</answer-text>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>if two galaxies are moving slowly enough, they may collide and then may not have enough velocity to escape each other's gravitational pull after the collision</exp> and that <exp>in this case&#8230;they eventually merge into a single galaxy</exp>. This means that <exp>two galaxies that cross paths may merge into one larger galaxy</exp>. This answer provides critical information to support the topic of <exp><b>what occurs when galaxies cross paths</b></exp> and is therefore one of the correct answers to this question.
</explain-text>
</answer>
</answer-list>
<key>0.1..2</key>
</question>                                                                                        </question-list>   

