<?xml version='1.0'?>
<script>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='AML11G1.jpg'>Listen to a discussion in a botany class.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:03' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G2.jpg'>Today, we have a topic I'm certain you're going to enjoy. The topic for today is one kind of tree and its products, products I'm sure most of you enjoy. We're going to talk about the cacao tree and some of the products we get from this tree. Just what products do we get from the cacao tree? Joe?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Joe' graphic-file='AML11G2.jpg'>The products we get from the cacao tree are some of my favorites: cocoa and chocolate.</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G2.jpg'>And where are cacao trees found? Yes. Ellen?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Ellen' graphic-file='AML11G2.jpg'>Um&#8230;cacao trees're native to the coastal areas of, um,  Mexico, Central America, and South America. Today, in addition to Mexico, Central, and South America, cacao trees are also found along the west coast of uh, Af-, of Africa and on a number of tropical islands.</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G2.jpg'>Yes, it's true that cacao trees're found in coastal areas of Central and South America as well as in Africa.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:01:09' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'>Let's look at this cacao tree. Can you describe the cacao tree for me? Taylor?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Taylor' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'>Well, you can see that the cacao tree has long, thick, shiny leaves; it's a type of evergreen tree.</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'>That's right. It's an evergreen. But what does it mean that it's an evergreen tree? It stays green all the time? Is that what you mean?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Taylor' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'>Ah&#8230;OK, I remember. An evergreen is any plant that keeps its leaves throughout the year. Many people think that only pines and&#8230;and firs are evergreens, but in reality, a lot of plants with broad leaves are evergreens. </paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'>And what about the fruit of the cacao tree? Joe?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Joe' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'><exp>What about the fruit</exp>?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'>You don't know?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Joe' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'><exp>I'm not sure</exp>&#8230;</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'><b><exp>Come on, we've talked about this before</exp>.</b> OK, what about you, Ellen? Can you tell me about the fruit of the cacao tree?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Ellen' graphic-file='AML11G3.jpg'>I&#8230;yeah&#8230;I think so&#8230;um&#8230;the fruit of the cacao tree is the size of a large cucumber and can be a variety of colors, depending on the type of tree.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:02:24' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G4.jpg'>And where does chocolate come from? From which part of the tree? Ellen?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Ellen' graphic-file='AML11G4.jpg'>Chocolate actually comes from the seeds of the fruit. Each piece of fruit contains a number of seeds. The seeds are roasted and then ground, and this gives us chocolate.</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G4.jpg'>And what is cocoa? How does cocoa differ from chocolate? Taylor?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Taylor' graphic-file='AML11G4.jpg'>Well, as Ellen explained, chocolate is the product that comes from the seeds of the cacao tree. To get chocolate, the seeds're first roasted and then ground. Cocoa's made from chocolate. Chocolate has a high fat content, and cocoa is chocolate that's had most of the fat removed.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:03:12' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G5.jpg'>It's very easy to confuse the words <i>cacao, cocoa,</i> and <i>chocolate</i>. Can you summarize what cacao, cocoa, and chocolate are, Joe?</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='Joe' graphic-file='AML11G5.jpg'>Yes, I think I can. <i>Cacao</i>, which is spelled C-A-C-A-O, is the name of the tree, <i>chocolate</i> is the roasted and ground seeds of the fruit of the cacao tree, and <i>cocoa</i>, which is spelled C-O-C-O-A, is a product that results when much of the fat is removed from chocolate.</paragraph>
<paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='AML11G5.jpg'>Very good. You all seem to understand this material very well.</paragraph>
</page>
</script>
