<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='AML12G1.jpg'>Listen to a lecture in a psychology class.</paragraph></page><page><paragraph time='00:00:03' speaker='professor' graphic-file='AML12G2.jpg'>We've been reading about how people's perceptions often differ from reality. What does this mean, that perceptions differ from reality? Yes?</paragraph><paragraph   speaker='student' graphic-file='AML12G2.jpg'>Well, it means that people may think something's true when, in reality, it's not&#8230;I mean, when the opposite is true.</paragraph><paragraph   speaker='professor' graphic-file='AML12G2.jpg'>Yes, that's what it means when perceptions differ from reality. Now, today we're going to look at a really clear case where certain perceptions held by Americans can differ considerably from reality. The example I'm using today is about what Americans think about multimillionaires and what researchers have discovered to be true about multimillionaires.</paragraph></page><page><paragraph time='00:00:47' speaker='professor' graphic-file='AML12G3.jpg'>For class today you were supposed to answer the short questionnaire about millionaires that I handed out last week. Do you have your questionnaires with you? Let's take a look at them. How many of you felt that the typical American multimillionaire would drive a new car? How about a five-year-old car? How many of you thought the typical American multimillionaire would prefer to eat caviar or other expensive foods? How many of you guessed club sandwiches? How many of you felt that a typical American multimillionaire spent over $1,000 on a suit? How many of you guessed it was under $400? And finally, how many of you felt that the typical American multimillionaire used cents-off coupons when buying food and household products? And, how many did not? Let's see a show of hands&#8230;wow&#8230;not too many of you have your hands up&#8230;. Well, you're in the same ballpark with most people. Most people think that the typical American multimillionaire has the most expensive car, the most expensive food, and the most expensive clothes, and doesn't worry about pennies, and you seem to have the same idea.<br/><br/>Now, remember our main point, that perceptions can differ from reality. Several studies've been done about how perceptions of really wealthy Americans differ from real American multimillionaires. Across the board, Americans have an image of multimillionaires spending a whole lot of money, perhaps quite carelessly. Although there is a certain percentage of wealthy people who fit this image or parts of it, studies have shown that the majority of American multimillionaires look like ordinary people. They drive old vehicles, eat everyday American food, shop at discount stores, use coupons, and are very, very frugal. In fact, typical wealthy Americans live under their means. They save money when everyone else is spending.</paragraph></page><page><paragraph time='00:03:05' speaker='professor' graphic-file='AML12G4.jpg'>Today, I'm going to give you five case studies of typical American multimillionaires. For next week, I'd like you to read the case studies and see if they more closely fit the general American perception of the American multimillionaire or the findings of the studies we read about this week. See you Monday.</paragraph></page></script>