<?xml version='1.0'?>
<script>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ASL04G1.jpg'>Listen to two students discussing a zoology course.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:04' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G2.jpg'>Now, we can move on to discuss the next part of the chapter, the part on land tortoises.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G2.jpg'>Yes. Land tortoises are tortoises that don't live in the water, although they may live near the water. They only come to the water to drink or bathe.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:21' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G3.jpg'>Oh, look here in the book. Here's a picture of one of the 40 kinds of land tortoises.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G3.jpg'>
Land tortoises are the ones that live to such long ages, aren't they?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G3.jpg'>Yes, my favorite part of the chapter was the part that was about how long land tortoises can really live.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G3.jpg'>How old can they live to be?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G3.jpg'>It's not really known for sure. There are lots of traditional stories about tortoises that lived for hundreds of years. I do remember hearing, when I was young, about tortoises that were supposed to be one- to two-hundred years old.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G3.jpg'>That couldn't be&#8230;No way.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G3.jpg'>Well, there're a lot of stories, but there're no accurate records, so it's impossible to verify whether or not they're true.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:01:08' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>Well, how old is the oldest tortoise on record, do you know?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>In the chapter I just read, it said that the oldest tortoise whose age can be verified to some extent is the one known as Marion's tortoise.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>I read that Marion's tortoise was 152 years old.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>Actually, I think the book said it was at least 152 years old. It was probably older.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>So, they're not really certain how old Marion's tortoise really was when it died. What is truly known about Marion's tortoise?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>It's certain that a French explorer named de Fresne, Marion de Fresne captured an adult tortoise in 1766, and he transported the tortoise to the island of Mauritius in that same year.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>Well, when did Marion's tortoise die? Are there authentic records?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>Historians are satisfied with the authenticity of the records that show that Marion's tortoise died in 1918.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>How do they know it was the same tortoise? Could it have been a different tortoise that died there in 1918?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>Tortoises don't occur naturally on Mauritius, so Marion's tortoise was the only tortoise on the island of Mauritius.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>And so this tortoise had been on the island of Mauritius for 152 years when it died.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>That's right. Marion's tortoise arrived in Mauritius in 1766 and died in 1918, so that would make it at least 152 years old.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>But didn't you say that the tortoise that was captured and brought to Mauritius by Marion de Fresne was an adult when it was captured?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>Yes. <b>So Marion's tortoise was known to have lived for 152 years on Mauritius. But because it was an adult when it was captured in 1766 and it's unclear how old it was at that time, it could have been considerably older than 152 years when it died, maybe 180 years or more. <u><exp>Two hundred years old for this type of tortoise isn't inconceivable</exp>.</u></b></paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>So a tortoise living to the age of 200 may be possible, but there're no verified records of such a tortoise.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL04G4.jpg'>Exactly!</paragraph>
</page>
</script>
