<?xml version='1.0'?>
<script>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ASL08G1.jpg'>Listen to a discussion by a group of students taking a course in American literature.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:05' speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G2.jpg'>I'm so glad we've been getting together each week to discuss this American literature class.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G2.jpg'>So am I. It makes it so much easier to comprehend everything when we discuss it together.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ASL08G2.jpg'>Yes, and it's going to make the final exam in this course so much easier for us. Because we've been meeting regularly since the beginning of the quarter, we'll be so prepared at the end of the course when that exam comes around.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G2.jpg'>Now, let's see. Where are we in this course?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G2.jpg'>I've got my syllabus right here. Let's look over what's going on this week.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ASL08G2.jpg'>Today's Thursday of the seventh week of the quarter, and this's the week on Edgar Allen Poe.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G2.jpg'>And here's a picture of Poe.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:48' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G3.jpg'>It's on page 234 of the text. This's the man who wrote everything we're reading this week. Now, where are we on the syllabus?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G3.jpg'><exp>So far, we covered Poe's literary criticism in class on Monday and one of Poe's short stories, "The Fall of the House of Usher," yesterday. We'll be dealing with Poe's famous poem, "The Raven," in tomorrow's class.</exp></paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G3.jpg'>Let's review Monday's class first. In that class, we discussed Poe as a literary critic.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:01:21' speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ASL08G4.jpg'>Right. Poe's most famous piece of literary criticism was his review of a book of short stories by Nathaniel Hawthorne, the one we read for Monday's class.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G4.jpg'>I think the main point of Poe's literary review of Hawthorne's book was his emphasis on the need for unity in short stories.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G4.jpg'>Didn't Poe compare the short story to the novel in this review of Hawthorne?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G4.jpg'>Well, he emphasized that the novel and the short story are different: a successful novel can have a variety of different elements, but a successful short story can't.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ASL08G4.jpg'>A successful short story needs to be unified, to have everything lead to one unified whole.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G4.jpg'>OK. I think we've got the main point of Poe's literary criticism. Now, let's move on to Wednesday's class.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G4.jpg'>I liked Wednesday's class a lot more than Monday's. I didn't enjoy reading the literary criticism for Monday, but I really liked the short story on Wednesday.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:02:20' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G5.jpg'>Well, Poe's especially famous for his short stories, and "The Fall of the House of Usher" is certainly one of his best known.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ASL08G5.jpg'>And for good reason. It really creates a terrifying mood and pulls the reader into the story.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G5.jpg'>I couldn't put it down until I finished it. I even went back and read it a second time to try and understand more of the details.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G5.jpg'>Poe certainly followed his own advice, the advice he gave in his literary criticism. Every detail contributed to the unity of the story.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ASL08G5.jpg'>I think that's the point the professor wanted us to get.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:02:55' speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G6.jpg'>Now, for tomorrow, we're supposed to read Poe's famous poem, "The Raven."</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G6.jpg'>I hope it won't take too long to read.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ASL08G6.jpg'>I've already finished it, and I'm sure you'll like it. If you liked the short story, then you'll really like the poem.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:03:10' speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G7.jpg'>That's it for today?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASL08G7.jpg'>Sorry. That's it for me. I have to be at my job in the library in about 15 minutes, and I don't want to be late. I have to run. I'll see you two in class tomorrow.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ASL08G7.jpg'>And see you a week from today for our next discussion.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ASL08G7.jpg'>See you.</paragraph>
</page>
</script>
