<?xml version='1.0'?>
<script>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ATL04G1.jpg'>Listen as an instructor leads a discussion on some material from an astronomy class.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:05' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G2.jpg'>Today we're talking about the life cycle of a star. I hope you've all read that chapter because we're going to be talking about it today. First of all, where does a star get its energy? Sally?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Sally' graphic-file='ATL04G2.jpg'>A star needs hydrogen to exist. The hydrogen fuels nuclear reactions, and these nuclear reactions are the source of the star's energy.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G2.jpg'>What happens when a star begins to exhaust its supply of hydrogen? Rob?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Rob' graphic-file='ATL04G2.jpg'>Uh&#8230;well&#8230;</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G2.jpg'>Maybe someone else could try answering the question&#8230;Doug, what happens when a star begins to exhaust its supply of hydrogen?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Rob' graphic-file='ATL04G2.jpg'>When a star begins to exhaust its supply of hydrogen, its life cycle is coming to an end. It becomes an old-aged star.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G2.jpg'>That's right, Doug. And what happens as a star heads into old age? Cathy?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Cathy' graphic-file='ATL04G2.jpg'>The first sign of old age is that the star begins to swell and to turn red in its outer regions. It's called a red giant.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:01:12' speaker='Cathy' graphic-file='ATL04G3.jpg'>This picture shows an example of a red giant. It shows a star that has swollen and turned red.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G3.jpg'>Now let's talk about our Sun and see where it is in its life cycle. Is our Sun a red giant? Doug?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Doug' graphic-file='ATL04G3.jpg'>Our Sun is an average size, middle-aged star. It's been in existence for about five and a half billion years, and it will most likely become a red giant in about five billion years.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G3.jpg'>So, as a star ages, it begins using up its supply of hydrogen, and it swells and begins turning red.</paragraph>
</page> 
<page>
<paragraph time='00:01:49' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G4.jpg'>What happens when all the hydrogen is used up? Sally?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Sally' graphic-file='ATL04G4.jpg'>When all the hydrogen's used up, the star collapses and dies.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G4.jpg'>That's right. When its hydrogen is depleted, a star collapses. But do all stars collapse in the same way? Rob?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Rob' graphic-file='ATL04G4.jpg'>Uh&#8230;yes, they do&#8230;they all collapse in the same way.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G4.jpg'>You sure, Rob? Maybe you'll want to read the assignment more carefully next time, Rob. Now, Cathy, what if you try the question. Do all stars collapse in the same way?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Cathy' graphic-file='ATL04G4.jpg'>No, all stars don't collapse in the same way. When a star collapses, it can become either a white dwarf or a supernova.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:02:37' speaker='Cathy' graphic-file='ATL04G5.jpg'>The picture on the left shows a white dwarf, and the one on the right shows a supernova.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G5.jpg'>Can you tell us some more about white dwarfs and supernovas?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Cathy' graphic-file='ATL04G5.jpg'>What happens when a star collapses basically depends on the size of the star. If a star is small, it collapses gently and remains collapsed. This is called a white dwarf. In contrast, if a star is large, there's a violent explosion when the star collapses, and the star is blown to bits. This is called a supernova.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G5.jpg'>What about our Sun? What do you think will happen to it? Do you think it'll end its life as a supernova? Rob, what's your thought on this?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Rob' graphic-file='ATL04G5.jpg'>Well, I'm not sure, but I think it'll end as a supernova.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G5.jpg'>You do? Do you agree, Doug?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Doug' graphic-file='ATL04G5.jpg'>Not exactly. Our Sun is a middle-size star, so it's probably not big enough to cause a supernova explosion.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:03:41' speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G6.jpg'>That's right. So what do you think will happen to it? One more chance, Rob.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Rob' graphic-file='ATL04G6.jpg'>Will it become a white dwarf?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G6.jpg'>You don't sound too sure, Rob, but that's exactly right. Our Sun is expected to end its life as a white dwarf. But we don't have too much to worry about because that's not going to happen for another 5 billion years. Now, even though our Sun is most likely not going to become a supernova, let's talk a bit more about what happens when there's a supernova. Sally, how about if you tell us.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='Sally' graphic-file='ATL04G6.jpg'>OK, I'll give it a try. When a star explodes in a supernova, it breaks into bits. These bits mix with hydrogen from the universe and form other stars. Our Sun was formed in just this way. Our Sun was formed from the remains of numerous other stars that had exploded earlier.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='instructor' graphic-file='ATL04G6.jpg'>Good. I hope you've all understood the basics of the life cycle of a star, particularly of our Sun, though I'm not sure all of you do. I'll see you next week for our next session.</paragraph>
</page>
</script>
