<?xml version='1.0'?>
<script>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ATL12G1.jpg'>Listen to a group of students discussing a lecture from an oceanography course.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:00:05' speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>That was a fascinating lecture, wasn't it?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>It certainly was, and that's good because <exp>we need to understand the information from the lecture for the next exam</exp>.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>Yeah, I really enjoyed the lecture, too, but I'm&#8230;uh&#8230;not looking forward to the exam. Do you want to discuss the information from the lecture to make sure we understand the key points?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>Sounds like a good idea to me. That way, we'll all be better prepared for the next exam.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>Sounds good to me, too.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>You know, before the lecture, I had no idea that there was so much life at the bottom, at the&#8230;bottom of the ocean.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>Neither did I.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>For a long time, scientists thought there was little or no life at the bottom of the ocean.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>Because it's so cold?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>Well, not just because it's so cold, but also because of the lack of sunlight.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>But now they know there's a tremendous amount of life at the bottom of the ocean, sometimes as much as four miles down. Four miles!</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>It's hard to even believe the ocean can be four miles deep.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>In some places it is, and when it's that deep, obviously, no sunlight can get down there.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>And some of the animal life down at the bottom of the ocean is huge. Did you notice that picture of the giant worms and giant shellfish?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>Yeah, and that really huge shark.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>And those animals are able to exist down there because of the black smokers.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G2.jpg'>The black smokers? I didn't quite understand that part of the lecture. Could you explain it?</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:01:43' speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G3.jpg'>Sure. I copied this picture of the black smokers during the lecture. See.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G3.jpg'>They look like volcanoes, don't they?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G3.jpg'>Well, that's because they actually are volcanoes on the ocean floor.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G3.jpg'>There are some volcanically active areas on the ocean floor. Water gets heated in the volcanoes, and jets of extraordinarily hot water shoot out.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G3.jpg'>These underwater volcanoes are called black smokers because, when the hot, hot water shoots out, it looks like black smoke.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G3.jpg'>And this water from the black smokers heats up the cold, cold water around them.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G3.jpg'>So life is able to exist on the bottom of the ocean because the black smokers heat up the water so that it's not too cold.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:02:32' speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>The black smokers do more than provide heat to support life. They also provide food.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>There's no food on the bottom of the ocean?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>Well, no food as we know it because there's no sunlight. Most of the world's living creatures depend on sunlight for food, in one way or another, through photosynthesis.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>I see. But deep in the ocean, there's no sunlight.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>And if there's no sunlight, photosynthesis isn't possible.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>That's one of the main reasons why scientists used to believe that life wasn't possible at the bottom of the ocean, where there was no sunlight.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>Scientists now know there's a tremendous amount of thriving life down in the depths of the ocean around the black smokers.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>But this life can't depend on photosynthesis because there's no sunlight.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G4.jpg'>That's right. Life in the depths of the ocean is dependent on chemosynthesis rather than photosynthesis.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:03:31' speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G5.jpg'>Chemosynthesis? How do you spell it? C-H-E-M-O-S-Y-N-T-H-E-S-I-S? So, it's dependent on chemicals rather than light?</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G5.jpg'>Yeah. The volcanic water heated by the earth's inner core is full of minerals. When the heated water erupts from the black smokers, bacteria around the black smokers are able to metabolize the minerals. Then the bacteria are eaten by other forms of life.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 1' graphic-file='ATL12G5.jpg'>So the minerals nourish the bacteria, and the bacteria nourish other life forms.</paragraph>
</page>
<page>
<paragraph time='00:04:11' speaker='man 1' graphic-file='ATL12G6.jpg'>That's exactly right. Life is dependent on the minerals from the black smokers. This is the only environment on earth where life that's totally independent of the energy of the sun is known to exist. The energy that supports these life forms comes from the earth itself.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='woman 2' graphic-file='ATL12G6.jpg'>That's truly amazing.</paragraph>
<paragraph   speaker='man 2' graphic-file='ATL12G6.jpg'>It is. It's also pretty wonderful that we seem to understand this material and are a little better prepared for the exam.</paragraph>
</page>
</script>
