<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>Now listen to a conversation between two students.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>Lynn, do you really think we need to work on this assignment now?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>John, we have this assignment to work on, and we have to do it together, and we have only two weeks until it's due.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>That's right, Lynn. It's not due for two weeks. So why do we need to do it now?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>John, I want to get it done early. I don't like waiting until the last second to do work. I like getting things done early.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>That's not really my style. That's not how I get things done.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>It's not? When do you want to work on this?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>Well, it's not due for two weeks, so next week, maybe?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>But the professor gave us this assignment this morning and gave us only two weeks to finish it. If we start now, we can finish it easily and not have to put it off until the last minute. It's really better this way.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>(<i>uncertainly</i>) If you say so, Lynn.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>Look, I've put together a schedule for us.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>A schedule?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>Yes. The schedule lists everything we need to do for this assignment. I've broken the assignment down into parts and then assigned parts to each of us and put a date next to each part. This way, we can get the assignment done bit by bit over the next two weeks.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>Listen, why don't we agree on who's going to do each part, and then you can get your parts done bit by bit over the next two weeks, and I can get my parts done when I want.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>You don't want to follow my schedule?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>I'd prefer to get this done on my own schedule.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>And you don't want us to work on this at the same time? You want us each to work on our own.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS06G1.jpg'>That sounds good to me.</paragraph></page></script>