<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='AMS09G1.jpg'>Listen to part of a talk in a linguistics class.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='professor' graphic-file='AMS09G1.jpg'>We've been talking about the fact that nouns can be countable or uncountable. There can be a countable noun such as <i>book</i>, and there can be an uncountable noun such as <i>happiness</i>. Some nouns can also have both countable and uncountable meanings. One such noun is <i>time</i>. We can talk about one time, two times, or three times, which is a countable use of <i>time</i>. We can also say that we don't have enough time, which is an uncountable use of <i>time</i>.<br/><br/>OK, today I'd like to give you another example of this. Let's talk about the noun <i>man</i>. Do you think the noun <i>man</i> is countable or uncountable? Well, <i>man</i> is a countable noun when it's used in reference to one man or two men, and the noun <i>man</i> is usually used this way. But it can also be used in an uncountable way, as in the history of man. This is an uncountable use of the noun <i>man</i>, and it means, in general, something like <i>humanity</i> or <i>mankind</i>.<br/><br/>Now for that example I promised you. Well, on July 20, 1969, when Neil Armstrong became the first person to step on the moon, he transmitted the famous statement, "One small step for a man, one giant leap for mankind."  In this statement, he was trying to say that when <u>one</u> man took a step on the moon, this step represented a giant leap forward for all of mankind. Unfortunately, however, when this statement was transmitted, the countable singular article <i>a</i> was inaudible; there was some sort of glitch in the transmission. Listeners on Earth thought that Armstrong said, "One small step for man&#8230;," and the effect of the omission of the article <i>a</i> in front of <i>man</i> was to change the meaning from one countable singular man on the moon to the uncountable mass <i>man</i> representing all of humanity. The quote as it was heard here on Earth didn't make much sense because the one small step in the quotation was taken by a countable singular man on the moon rather than by all of humanity. Armstrong has indicated that he actually said, "One small step for <u>a</u> man&#8230;," which makes more sense, but that's not what was heard here on Earth.</paragraph></page></script>