<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Now listen to a conversation between two students.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Hi, Sandy.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Oh, hi, Dave. I'm glad to see you. Listen, you live in an apartment now, don't you?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Yes, I lived in the dorm for two years, and then I moved into an apartment earlier this year. Are you still living in the dorm?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Yes, but I'm thinking about moving into an apartment.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Oh, you want to move out of the dorm?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>No, not exactly. I'm living in the dorm, in a suite with three roommates. I like my roommates a lot, and I'm happy living in the dorm.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Then why are you thinking about moving to an apartment?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Well, my roommates want to move to an apartment, and I'm really happy living with them&#8230;I really like them&#8230;so I guess I have to think about moving to an apartment with them.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Well, if you're thinking about moving into an apartment, then you should consider that you'll have more responsibilities in an apartment, you have to pay rent and take care of bills, stuff like that.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>I can do that if I have to.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>And you have to shop for food and cook for yourself.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>Oh, I don't like to cook so much&#8230;but if it's so much work to live in an apartment, why aren't you living in the dorm?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>There are too many rules in the dorm. I like having my own apartment so I don't have to worry about following so many rules, and I have a lot more privacy in my apartment than I had in the dorm.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>So you think I should move into an apartment with my friends?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS12G1.jpg'>I think you'll have to make up your own mind.</paragraph></page></script>