<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>Now listen to two students as they discuss the section of the catalogue.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>What's your major, Carl?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>My major's engineering.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>Wow, so you've been accepted by the engineering department as an engineering major?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>What do you mean?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>You need to apply to the engineering department to be accepted as an engineering major, you know. Have you done that yet?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>No, I haven't, but I'm sure I'll be accepted when I do.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>You're sure? Why?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>Well, I've taken most of the prerequisites, and I have a B average. The catalogue says that we need a B average for an engineering major.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>The catalogue says that you need a B average to apply to be accepted as an engineering major. It doesn't promise you'll be admitted with a B average, only that you can apply with a B average.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>It does? I thought I was OK with a B average, that I was sure to be admitted with a B average, that is.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>I don't think so. The catalogue says that you have to have a B average to <u>apply</u>, and I heard that last year only about half of the people who applied were actually accepted to the program. That means that a lot of students with B averages weren't admitted.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>Oh, no! That doesn't sound too promising.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>Well, you said that you've taken <u>most</u> of the prerequisite courses but not <u>all</u> of them?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>That's right.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>Well, maybe you need to get really high grades in the rest of the prerequisite courses if you want to have a better chance of being accepted as an engineering major.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS14G1.jpg'>I'm certainly going to try to do that!</paragraph></page></script>