<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Now listen to a conversation between two students.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Hey, Carol! Do you have a minute? I'd like to ask you something.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Yeah, Sam, sure. What's your question?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>I'd like to ask you about the statistics class, the lower division one. You took it already, didn't you?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>I sure did, and I even survived it!</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Survived it? You mean it was hard?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Really hard.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Oh, well, that may answer my question.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>What's your question? You're thinking about whether or not to take it? You have to take it, you know. It's required for our major.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Yeah, I know I have to take it, and if it's that hard, I'm not looking forward to taking it. My question's not about whether or not to take it, it's about when to take it.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>You should take it soon because it's a prerequisite for some other courses you need to take.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Yeah, I know. My question's this. The lower division statistics course is offered in the summer session and then it's also offered again in the fall session. I'm wondering if I should take it this summer or if I should wait and take it in the fall.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>What's the difference between how it's offered in the summer and in the fall?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>In the summer, it's a really concentrated course. It meets for five hours a day Monday through Friday for two weeks. In the fall, the course is spread out over ten weeks. It sounds good to me that the course is over in only two weeks in the summer.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS24G1.jpg'>Well, it may sound good to you to get it over with in two weeks in the summer, but I wouldn't do it that way. I can't imagine trying to get all of the reading assignments done in only two weeks. It was even hard for me to get all of it done over a ten-week session. The course covers so much difficult information that I would have preferred to have it spread out over even more weeks. </paragraph></page></script>