<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>Now listen to two students as they discuss the notice.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>Did you see the notice that was posted?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>The one about Friday night's guest speaker? I saw the one that said there would be a guest speaker on Friday evening, and I want to go listen to the speaker.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>No, sorry, there's a later notice. The later notice announces that the event Friday evening featuring the guest speaker has been canceled.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>Cancelled? But why? Couldn't the speaker make it here?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>No, that's not the reason the event's been canceled. The event was canceled because there was so much controversy about it.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>I can't believe that. I mean, I know this guest speaker is quite controversial, but this is a university, and there's supposed to be a free exchange of ideas here.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>I know what you mean. I know how to listen to a controversial speaker and decide for myself if what he or she is saying makes sense. I'm really disappointed the event has been canceled.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>So am I. I was excited when I saw the notice announcing that this guest speaker was coming to campus. Now I'm really unhappy to hear that he's not coming.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>Me, too. I'm disappointed to hear that the event has been canceled, but I'm even more disappointed to hear why.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='AMS20G1.jpg'>So am I!</paragraph></page></script>