<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>Now listen to two students as they discuss the article.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>I was at the game last night, and I swear that the newspaper got it all wrong.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>The newspaper had incorrect information? Like what?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>The newspaper said it was a large number of spectators who ran out onto the field for no reason, but it wasn't. It was only two people who ran out onto the field, and it was two parents, and they had a good reason to run out onto the field. Their son was playing in the game, and he got hurt.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>Was that all that was wrong in the newspaper article?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>No, there were a lot more errors. The newspaper said there was a lot of pushing and shoving, but there wasn't. There were just two parents who were trying to get to their son. And something else that was wrong was that their son got hurt in the scuffle when everybody ran out on the field, but he didn't; he got hurt playing in the game.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>My goodness! That's a lot of mistakes in a short article.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>But that's not all that was wrong! The article said that the police were called to break up the scuffle, but the police weren't called because there was no scuffle to break up. Also, an ambulance didn't come to take the guy to the hospital, like the article said; the parents drove their son home because he wasn't seriously injured.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>Are you sure he wasn't injured too seriously?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS09G1.jpg'>Absolutely! I saw him in class this morning, and he was just fine!</paragraph></page></script>