<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>Now listen to a conversation between two students.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>Hi, John.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>Hi, Cathy.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>What's up, John? You look worried.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>Oh, I'm not worried, Cathy. I just have a big decision to make, and I'm not sure what to do. I'm confused, not worried.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>Anything I can help with?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>It's about my schedule for next semester.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>You haven't finished with your schedule for next semester yet? Schedules are due by the end of the day today. But I'm sure you know that.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>I do, and I have just one more decision to make before I turn my schedule in. Maybe you can help me with this decision.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>What are you trying to decide?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>I need to figure out how many courses to take.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>That should be an easy decision. A full-time schedule is four courses. Are you thinking of taking only a part-time schedule, maybe two or three courses?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>No, it's not that. I'm thinking that maybe I should take five courses instead of four.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'><u>Five</u> courses? But four courses is a full-time schedule. You want to take more than a full-time schedule? That would be a whole lot of work. For me, well, I couldn't handle more than four courses. Say, why are you thinking of taking five courses?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>I'm thinking that if I take an extra course each semester, I can graduate early.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>But that means you'll have to spend all your time studying, and you wouldn't be able to do anything else. Tell me, how are you doing this semester? You're taking four courses now, aren't you?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>Yes, I'm taking four courses, and I'm doing OK.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>You're doing just <u>OK</u> in four classes? Not <u>well</u>?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>Just OK.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS14G1.jpg'>If you're not doing really well in four courses, do you really want to try five courses?</paragraph></page></script>