<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ASS17G1.jpg'>Now listen to part of a talk in an American history class.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='professor' graphic-file='ASS17G1.jpg'>Today, I'll be talking about the Underground Railroad and about a woman whose name is closely associated with the Underground Railroad, Harriet Tubman. The Underground Railroad was a loosely structured network to help slaves escape from Southern states in the period of time before the Civil War. You should note that the Underground Railroad was NOT either underground or a railroad. Slaves escaping along the Underground Railroad sometimes traveled hidden in a boat or a wagon, but they mostly traveled on foot. They generally traveled at night, when it was safer to move, and hid during the day. This escape route was called a railroad because it was a method of helping slaves to move and not because it involved railroad cars moving along tracks. It was described as being underground because it was secret, not because any of the travel was beneath the surface of the earth.<br/><br/>Railroad terminology was used to describe the system for assisting slaves in escaping. The term "passengers" was used to refer to the slaves who were trying to escape; the "conductors" were the people who helped the slaves along their path to freedom; "stations" were safe houses where the slaves could hide during their escape. Thus, the statement that a conductor directed a passenger to a different station really meant that someone along the escape route helped an escaping slave to get to a new hiding place.<br/><br/>Harriet Tubman was a person who figured prominently in the history of the Underground Railroad. She herself had been a slave who escaped from slavery in the South using the Underground Railroad. Following her escape from slavery in the period prior to the Civil War, Harriet Tubman returned repeatedly to the South to help other slaves escape to the North. She's known to have made the dangerous return trip back to the South at least 19 times and to have led at least 300 escaping slaves to freedom in the North.</paragraph></page></script>