<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>Now listen to a conversation between two students.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>Hi, Mark.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>Hi, Jane.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>We have that paper to write for Professor Hadley's class.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>I know, and I'm not looking forward to doing it.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>You mean you haven't even started yours yet?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>No, I haven't.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>Well, I wanted to ask you how you're going to go about it.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>What do you mean?  We're supposed to write a paper, so I'm going to sit down and write it.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>You're not going to outline your paper first before you write it?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>No, I don't usually make outlines, unless the outline is part of the assignment. You really do?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>Yes, I do. I usually spend a lot of time making an outline before I write something. I've been working on the outline for this paper for a couple of days now.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>You've already spent a couple of days on the outline for this paper? I can't believe that. I can't believe you need to spend several days making an outline for this assignment.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>That's what I need to do to make sure that my paper's really organized. You know the professor said that he wanted a really well-organized paper, don't you? How are you going to make sure that your paper's well-organized if you don't make a detailed outline before you write the paper?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>Well, I just write it first, and look at what I've written, and then if I need to, I organize it some more.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>And that works for you?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ASS13G1.jpg'>Works for me!</paragraph></page></script>