<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>Now listen to a conversation between two students.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>Hi, Jennifer. What's up?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>Oh, I've got a problem, and I don't know what to do about it. Maybe you can help me with it.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>I'm not sure if I can, but I'll try. What's the problem?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>It has to do with the tennis team.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>You're having a problem with the tennis team? But I thought you enjoyed being on the team. You were so excited when you made the team!</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>Oh, it's not that. I love being on the team, and I've been doing really well on it. The problem is that I've been spending too much time on tennis, with all the practices and matches and tournaments and travel. I really love all of that. But, with all the time I've been spending on tennis, I'm not doing very well in my classes.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>Oh, that <u>is</u> a problem. You definitely need to put more time into your classes. It's really important for you to have good grades.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>But that's the problem. You're on the tennis team, and you still manage to get good grades. How do you do it? I seem to be spending so much time on tennis that I just don't have enough time for my classes.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>You just need to look at <u>how</u> you're spending your time. If you really think about how you spend your time each day, I'm sure you'll find out that you actually do have enough time for both tennis and your classes.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>What do you mean, that I should look at how I'm spending my time?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>Well, each day, you should look at all of the things you're scheduled to do, and then with the rest of your time <u>plan</u> when you're going to study. You should schedule your study time just the same way that you schedule your tennis practice.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>You mean, you think I should write down my schedule each day and write down study times on my daily schedule? Is that what you do?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>I do make a schedule each day, but I don't write the schedule down. I make a mental schedule, and this mental schedule includes lots of time for studying. But, maybe for a few weeks you should write down your schedule each day until it becomes natural for you to make better use of your time.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS05G1.jpg'>I think I could try that. Maybe it'll help.</paragraph></page></script>