<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Now listen to two students as they discuss the brochure.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Hi, Alice.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Oh, hi, Don.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Listen, Alice, you're thinking of getting the certificate in technical writing, too, aren't you?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Yes, I am. You mean, you're thinking about getting it, too?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>I am, but I'm a little confused about something.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>You are? About what?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Well, did you read the brochure about the certificate program?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Yes, I did.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Well, did you see the part about how many units are required?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Yes. The brochure said that 25 units are required. That doesn't sound like too much, does it? We can finish 25 units pretty quickly.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>You're right about that, but I just don't see how we can get a certificate with 25 units.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>You don't? But the brochure says that 25 units are required for the certificate.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Yes, it does, but then it says that there is an eight-unit introductory course that's required.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Yes, it does.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>And it says that the remaining units should be taken in elective courses.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>That's right, too.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Well, if 25 units are required and if eight of these units are in an introductory course, then that leaves 17 units, doesn't it?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Yes, it does, but I still don't see what the problem is.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>Well, here's the problem. Each of the elective courses is four units each, so if we take four elective courses, then that's 16 units.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>OK, now I see what the problem is. If all of the electives are four-unit courses, then there's no way to take just 25 units.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS09G1.jpg'>That's right. So we're going to have to take more than 25 units to get this certificate.</paragraph></page></script>