<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ATS06G1.jpg'>Now listen to a part of a talk about techniques for convincing people to do things.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='professor' graphic-file='ATS06G1.jpg'>Two techniques that people use to convince others to comply, or go along, with what they want are the <i>foot-in-the-door</i> technique and the <i>door-in-the-face</i> technique.<br/><br/>The foot-in-the-door technique builds up to a large request by starting with a small request. You want someone to do something large, like lending you a car, so you start by asking to borrow a bicycle. There's a tendency for a person to comply with a large request if he or she has previously complied with a small request. So if you want to borrow something large, like a car, from your neighbor, you don't go and ask for the car right off the bat. Instead, you start by asking to borrow a bicycle from this neighbor, and then there's a better possibility that this neighbor will lend you the big item, the car, later on. This is the foot-in-the-door technique, starting with a small request, like the bicycle, and then building up to something big, like the car.<br/><br/>The next technique is the door-in-the-face technique. It sounds something like the foot-in-the-door technique, but it's different; it's basically the opposite type of technique. The door-in-the face technique is when you want something small from someone else, your neighbor, perhaps, and you don't think the neighbor will agree to do it. So, you ask for something big, and the neighbor refuses, and then you follow this with a request for something small, and the neighbor feels guilty about refusing the big request and grants the small request. Using this type of technique, if you want to borrow something small from the neighbor, like the bicycle, instead of asking to borrow the bicycle first, you ask to borrow the neighbor's car first. When the neighbor refuses the request to borrow the car, you then follow up the request for the car with, "Well, can I at least borrow your bicycle?"  Then the neighbor, feeling really guilty about not lending you the car, agrees to lend you the bicycle, and it's the bicycle that you really wanted after all. This is the door-in-the-face technique, starting with a big request, like the car, and then accepting something small, like the bicycle.</paragraph></page></script>