<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='narrator' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Now listen to a conversation between two students.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Hi, Sara.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Hey, Peter, how are you doing?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Oh, fine, thanks. Listen, Sara, I have a question for you. Do you have some time?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Sure, I've got a few minutes before I head to class. What's your question?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>It's about Dr. Frank's sociology class.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Oh, you're taking that class? I took it last semester.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>I know. That's why I wanted to ask you about it.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>OK, I'll see if I can help. What do you want to know about?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Well, I'm really having trouble with the class. I'm thinking of dropping it because I don't think I can do very well in it.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Why aren't you doing well in it?</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>I'm having a lot of trouble understanding what the professor is talking about in class. I read all the assigned material before class, and I pay attention in class, but I just can't follow what he's talking about, so I can't take very good notes.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Oh, I know exactly what you mean. His lectures certainly don't follow along with what's in the assigned chapters in the text; his lectures kind of supplement the text, and, well, he does seem to jump around a lot talking about this and then all of a sudden talking about that. Here, let me tell you what I did because it worked for me. I got together with a couple of my classmates after each lecture, and we compared our notes. Usually we had completely different notes, so with the three of us together, we were usually able to figure out what all the main points of the lectures were.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='man' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>Maybe I'll try that. I'll have to see if some of my classmates are having as much trouble as I am understanding the lectures.</paragraph><paragraph time='00:00:00.00' speaker='woman' graphic-file='ATS11G1.jpg'>I'm sure they are.</paragraph></page></script>