<?xml version='1.0'?><essay><question-text>In some classes, course grades are based solely on exams, while in other classes, grades are based more on class participation than on exams. Which type of grading do you prefer? Use specific reasons to support your response.</question-text><sample-answer-text><tab/>Grades in some courses may be based either on exams or on class participation, and the professor should always choose the most appropriate grading for a course. However, for a typical course, I think that it is far more equitable to base course grades more on exam grades than on class participation. The following reasons support this opinion.<br/><tab/>Unless the class is very small (and most university classes tend to be rather large), it can be very difficult for all students to get a chance to take part equally in discussions. In fact, the bigger the class, the more difficult it is for each student to participate. In normal-sized classes, it is quite difficult for each student to express opinions and demonstrate knowledge to the professor because there is simply not enough time for this to take place. Then, considering that some students tend to monopolize class time whether or not they are more knowledgeable than the rest of the class, it can be difficult for students who do not easily dominate discussions to demonstrate their strong preparation for class, their mastery of the subject matter, and their ability to explain the material.<br/><tab/>Also, in a large class, it can be very difficult for the professor to evaluate fairly not only which students have mastered the material but also which students have not. The amount that a student speaks out in class is neither a clear indication nor an accurate measure of what the student has learned. It is not fair or accurate to assume that, because a particular student has not managed to speak out as much as other students in the class (particularly if there are many outspoken students in the class), the student has not learned as much as the others have. It is not fair to assume that the students who speak out most in class actually know the most.<br/><tab/>Thus, in regular class situations, it seems far better for a professor to base course grades on exam grades rather than on class participation. During an exam, each student has an equal opportunity to demonstrate what he or she has learned, and after the exam, the professor can more easily evaluate the exams in a way that is both consistent and fair.</sample-answer-text></essay>