<?xml version='1.0'?><essay><question-text>Sometimes an event that seems to be going badly turns out well after all. Discuss such an event in your life, using specific details to support your response.</question-text><sample-answer-text><tab/>It is quite possible for someone to have a day that does not seem to go well and for that day, in retrospect, to turn out quite well. I had just such a day a few years ago, a day that seemed awful in every way possible but turned out to be wonderful.<br/><tab/>I was studying at a university that was quite far from my home, and I had been away from home for six months. When school was closed for a long holiday weekend, I decided that I would spend the money for a plane ticket to go home. I bought a ticket that I really could not afford and then waited for the day of the trip with great anticipation. Unfortunately, on the day of the trip, the weather turned bad. I went to the airport anyway, hoping that by some miracle my flight would be able to take off. By the time I arrived at the airport, the weather had turned even worse.<br/><tab/>At the airport, it was announced that no airplanes would be able to take off for some time, that the roads around the airport were closed, and that no one could leave the airport. Instead of being able to go home and see my family, whom I missed so much, I was stuck in the airport, cold and alone. After I had been in the airport for about six hours, I was quite upset. This was not how I expected to be spending this vacation from school, sitting by myself on my suitcase on the floor of the airport.<br/><tab/>Then what had been a horrible day up until then began turning around. I noticed a quiet woman who was sitting nearby and smiling at me. I was surprised that someone could be smiling in the middle of this situation, but she was. We began talking, and then we talked some more. Another six hours passed, much more quickly than the previous six hours had passed because I was so involved in my conversation with this woman. After a total of twelve hours in the airport, the bad weather lifted, the roads opened, and the airplanes were allowed to take off. When it was announced that my flight would not be taking off until much later, I decided to return to school without going home.<br/><tab/>Now, you might be thinking that I was very upset about this experience because I did not get to go home to see my family, but this is not the case. Instead, this experience has turned out to be one of the most important events in my life: The woman whom I met in the airport is now my wonderful wife.</sample-answer-text></essay>