<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='timecode' speaker='professor' graphic-file='AMW05G1-s.jpg'>When the faculty heard the administrators' first point, that the administrators wanted to add a new classroom building, they were overjoyed because they recognized that the college truly needed more classroom space. However, the faculty strongly disagreed with the administrators about how the new classroom space would be used. The administrators wanted more classroom space so that more students could be admitted to the college. The faculty, however, strongly objected to the current overcrowded classes and wanted the additional classroom space so that class sizes could be decreased. If additional students were admitted to the college after a new classroom building was added, then the current high class size would continue.<br/><br/>The faculty then heard the administrators' second point about how the bequest should be spent, the point about a new gymnasium. The faculty recognized that the 70-year-old gymnasium was a problem, but instead of building an entirely new gymnasium, they believed that it was possible to renovate the current gymnasium and make additions to it rather than tearing it down.<br/><br/>Then the faculty heard the administrators' third point, and it was this point that really enraged the faculty. The faculty was aghast that the administrators wanted to spend part of the bequest on pay raises for themselves. Faculty members knew that it was true that administrative salaries at Dodgson were ten percent below the national average, but it was also true that faculty wages were below the national average, and the faculty members weren't asking for pay raises for themselves. The faculty strongly believed that any additional money in the bequest, after adding a new classroom building and refurbishing the old gymnasium, should be spent on scholarships for students so that the college could attract a higher caliber of students.</paragraph></page></script>