<?xml version='1.0'?><script><page><paragraph time='timecode' speaker='professor' graphic-file='AMW03G1-s.jpg'>Other examples of these phenomena of group behavior can be provided. In regard to the deindividualization that occurs in groups, it's quite true that people in large groups tend to lose their individuality and self-awareness and behave in ways that they normally would not if they were alone, and this type of behavior is known as deindividualistic behavior. This deindividualism can lead to prosocial behavior; deindividualistic behavior is not always antisocial. One example of prosocial deindividualistic behavior might be what can occur during a period of shared emotional pain after some sort of cataclysmic event when people band together as a group and take part in an outpouring of kindness as a group that they might not have taken part in individually. Another example of prosocial deindividualistic behavior might take place after an exciting contest that an underdog wins, when the audience members who are extraordinarily pleased at the results get caught up in an overwhelming display of approval, far more than any individual would display alone.<br/><br/>In regard to the polarization that takes place in groups, it's quite true that when like-minded people get together in a group, it's quite common for them to arrive at a decision that is far more extreme than a decision that any of the members of the group would have arrived at individually, and this type of behavior is known as polarization. This polarization doesn't always have to lead to antisocial behavior; it can also lead to prosocial behavior. One example of polarization that leads to prosocial behavior is the actions of a group of townspeople who, after suffering individually for years at the hands of the town bully, finally band together to rid the town of the bully. Another example of polarization that leads to prosocial behavior is a group of employees, who have suffered individually for years under a horrible and sadistic boss, who band together as a group to deal with the boss.</paragraph></page></script>