<?xml version='1.0'?><essay><question-text>What is your approach to problem-solving, and how does it work for you? Use specific details to support your response.</question-text><sample-answer-text><tab/>When I have a problem to solve in my life, I have an approach to problem-solving that has a significant benefit to it. However, this approach to solving my problems also has a weakness that I must try to minimize if I want to continue using this method and derive the benefits that it offers.<br/><tab/>I use the following approach when a problem arises in my life. First, I think about the problem myself, and only after I have given the problem considerable thought do I talk about it with my family and friends. After I listen to the opinions of my family and friends, I think some more about what they have said. At this point, I make my final decision. This approach has proven more beneficial to me than has other approaches in that it allows me to hear perspectives and opinions that someone else has thought of.<br/><tab/>Though this approach has worked fairly well for me, there are some problems in it that I would want to resolve if I were going to use it again. The biggest problem with this approach is that it sometimes creates difficulties for me with family and friends who have helped me by offering their opinions and advice when I do not always share the opinions or take the advice. In the past, there have been situations when a friend or family member has been hurt or upset that the advice offered to me was not followed.<br/><tab/>When I have a problem to deal with, I still absolutely want to involve my family and friends in my decision; all of their different perspectives are really helpful to me because it is quite possible that some of the issues involved in the decision are not completely clear to me. However, I need to work on getting across to my family and friends that, while their input is valuable to me, I might not always follow their recommendations if I think that something else is better. Even though I do not always follow their advice, their input on problems is valuable in helping me resolve these problems.</sample-answer-text></essay>