<?xml version='1.0'?><essay><question-text>Telecommuting (working for a company from home rather than in the office and communicating with the office by computer) is becoming more and more common. Discuss the advantages of telecommuting versus working in an office. Then indicate which you prefer and why.</question-text><sample-answer-text><tab/>There are many opportunities today for people to telecommute, to work at home rather than in the office and communicate with the office by computer. I myself have not yet had a single opportunity to telecommute; my work experience up to now has been in an accounting office where telecommuting is not an option. However, I would like to consider the relative advantages of telecommuting versus working in an office because I will quite possibly have an opportunity to telecommute sometime in the future.<br/><tab/>There seem to be several rather obvious advantages of telecommuting from home rather than working in an office. First of all, you can save a lot of time and money by not commuting to and from the office each day; you can spend a lot of time and money getting to and from work, and much of this could be saved through telecommuting. Also, you can probably have some control over your work hours by starting and stopping an hour or two earlier or later on a particular day. Finally, because of this flexibility with work hours, you would be able to deal with various crises as they arise; illnesses or different types of appointments are much easier to deal with in the flexible environment of telecommuting than in a traditional work environment.<br/><tab/>However, there are advantages to working in an office, and they should not be underrated. It can be much easier to work with others if there are daily face-to-face interactions, and this is a stimulus that you get only by working in an office and that does not happen if you are working at home. Also, the feeling of camaraderie that exists between workers who are together in an office makes working in an office more enjoyable than working alone at home. Finally, less self-motivation is required when working in an office than when working at home because a boss and coworkers are in an office to motivate you.<br/><tab/>There seem to be quite a few obvious advantages to telecommuting: the savings of time and money from not commuting to the office, the flexibility from not having set hours, and the ability to deal with problems as they arise. However, for me, it does not seem like the best choice at this point in my life. I am not sure that I have enough self-discipline to work as hard as I should if I do not have a boss and coworkers around me and set hours to be in the office, and I would certainly miss the day-to-day camaraderie that I get from going to the office.</sample-answer-text></essay>