<?xml version='1.0'?><question-list type='write' essay-file='ASW04P0.xml' notes-file='ASW04N.xml'><question type='select.word.1' essay-file='ASW04P1.xml' skills='8'><question-text>Click on the group of words in the essay question that indicates the main topic of the essay.</question-text><explain-text>The phrase <exp>type of family living arrangement</exp> indicates the main topic of the essay. <exp>Type of family living arrangement</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word.1' essay-file='ASW04P2.xml' skills='8'><question-text>Click on the group of words in the essay question that indicates what you should discuss about the topic.</question-text><explain-text>The third sentence in the essay question asks <exp>Which type of family arrangement do you think is the most beneficial?</exp>  This sentence indicates that you should indicate what is <exp>the most beneficial</exp> about the topic. <exp>The most beneficial</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word.1' essay-file='ASW04P3.xml' skills='8'><question-text>Click on the word or group of words in the essay question that indicates the type of supporting ideas that should be used to develop the topic.</question-text><explain-text>The word <exp>reasons</exp> in the essay question indicates the type of supporting ideas that should be used to develop the topic. <exp>Reasons</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.paragraph' essay-file='ASW04P4.xml' skills='9'><question-text>Click on the paragraph in the essay that serves as the introduction.</question-text><explain-text>The first paragraph in the essay serves as the introduction to the essay. Paragraph A is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW04P5.xml' skills='9'><question-text>Look at the introductory paragraph. Click on the sentence in the introduction that provides background information about the author.</question-text><explain-text>The second sentence of the introduction indicates that <exp>in my culture, and in my family, it is quite common for the extended family to live together</exp> and that <exp>my grandmother and one of my aunts actually live in the same house with my parents and brothers and sisters, and several other aunts and uncles live on the same block</exp>. This sentence provides background information about the author and is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW04P6.xml' skills='9'><question-text>Look at the introductory paragraph. Click on the sentence in the introduction that shows how the author feels about the topic.</question-text><explain-text>The last sentence of the introduction states that the author feels that <exp>there are several good reasons why living with the extended family is preferable to living with only the nuclear family</exp>. This sentence shows how the author feels about the topic and is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW04P7.xml' skills='9'><question-text>Look at the introductory paragraph. Click on the sentence in the introduction that shows how the essay will be organized.</question-text><explain-text>The last sentence of the introduction indicates that the essay will include <exp>several good reasons</exp>. This sentence shows how the essay will be organized and is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='multichoice' essay-file='ASW04P8.xml' skills='10'><question-text>How many supporting paragraphs does this essay have?</question-text><answer-list><answer-text>1</answer-text><answer-text>2</answer-text><answer-text>3</answer-text><answer-text>4</answer-text></answer-list><key>2</key><explain-text>This essay has four paragraphs overall. The first paragraph is the introduction, and the last paragraph is the conclusion. The two middle paragraphs are the suporting paragraphs. The second answer is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.paragraph' essay-file='ASW04P9.xml' skills='10'><question-text>Click on the supporting paragraph that provides a reason about the effort that it takes to run a family.<br/>Scroll the passage to see all of the paragraphs.<br/></question-text><explain-text>The first sentence of paragraph B mentions <exp>the day-to-day work of the family</exp>. From this, it can be determined that paragraph B provides a reason about the effort that it takes to run a family. Paragraph B is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.paragraph' essay-file='ASW04P10.xml' skills='10'><question-text>Click on the supporting paragraph that provides a reason about maintenance of the family heritage.<br/>Scroll the passage to see all of the paragraphs.<br/></question-text><explain-text>The first sentence of paragraph C mentions <exp>maintaining family traditions</exp>. From this, it can be determined that paragraph C provides a reason about maintenance of the family heritage. Paragraph C is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW04P11.xml' skills='11'><question-text>Click on the sentence containing the transition phrase that announces the first supporting paragraph.<br/>Scroll the passage to see all of the paragraphs.<br/></question-text><explain-text>The transition phrase <exp>One possible reason</exp> in the first sentence of paragraph B announces that this is the first supporting paragraph. The first sentence of paragraph B is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW04P12.xml' skills='11'><question-text>Click on the sentence in paragraph B containing the transition expression that indicates that another supporting detail follows.</question-text><explain-text>The last sentence in paragraph B contains the transition expression <exp>in addition</exp>, which indicates that another supporting detail follows. This sentence is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW04P13.xml' skills='11'><question-text>Click on the sentence that serves as a transition between the first and second supporting paragraphs.<br/>Scroll the passage to see all of the paragraphs.<br/></question-text><explain-text>The first sentence in paragraph C is a transition between the first and second paragraphs. It contains the topic of the first supporting paragraph <exp>the daily work of running a family</exp> and the topic of the second supporting paragraph <exp>maintaining family traditions</exp>. The first sentence of paragraph C is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word.2' essay-file='ASW04P14.xml' skills='10'><question-text>Click on the transition word or group of words in paragraph C that links the two supporting ideas in the paragraph.</question-text><explain-text>The word <exp>also</exp> links the supporting idea in the third sentence of paragraph C to the supporting idea in the second sentence of paragraph C. <exp>Also</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.paragraph' essay-file='ASW04P15.xml' skills='12'><question-text>Click on the paragraph that serves as a conclusion.<br/>Scroll the passage to see all of the paragraphs.<br/></question-text><explain-text>The last paragraph serves as the conclusion to the essay. Paragraph D is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW04P16.xml' skills='12'><question-text>Look at the concluding paragraph. Click on the sentence in the conclusion that gives the author's opinion about the topic of the essay.</question-text><explain-text>The first sentence of paragraph D states that <exp>having the extended family living together can be quite beneficial</exp>. From this, it can be determined that paragraph D gives the author's opinion about the topic. The first sentence of paragraph D is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW04P17.xml' skills='12'><question-text>Look at the concluding paragraph. Click on the sentence in the conclusion that summarizes the author's reasons.</question-text><explain-text>The second sentence of paragraph D mentions <exp>the mundane work of getting through the day</exp> and <exp>family traditions</exp> that are <exp>passed from one generation to the next</exp>. This sentence summarizes the author's reasons that the extended family should live together and is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question></question-list>