<?xml version='1.0'?><question-list type='write' passage-file='ASW02RP.xml' audio-file='ASW02.mp3' script-file='ASW02LS.xml' notes-file='ASW02N.xml' essay-file='ASW02P0.xml'><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW02P1.xml' skills='4'><question-text>Click on the sentence that shows how the ideas in the reading passage and the ideas in the listening passage are related.<br/>Scroll the passage to find the answer.</question-text><explain-text>The first sentence of paragraph A says that <exp>the reading passage discusses</exp> and that <exp>the listening passage discusses</exp>. From this, it can be determined that this sentence shows how the ideas in the reading passage and the ideas in the listening passage are related. The first sentence of paragraph A is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.paragraph' essay-file='ASW02P2.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the paragraph that discusses Jefferson's and Hamilton's beliefs about what the economy should be based on.<br/>Scroll the passage to find the answer.</question-text><explain-text>The first sentence of paragraph B says that <exp>one way that Jefferson and Hamilton disagreed was as to what the basis of the economy should be</exp>. From this, it can be determined that paragraph B discusses Jefferson's and Hamilton's beliefs about what the economy should be based on. Paragraph B is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.paragraph' essay-file='ASW02P3.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the paragraph that discusses Jefferson's and Hamilton's beliefs about what the relationship between the states and the central government should be.<br/>Scroll the passage to find the answer.</question-text><explain-text>The first sentence of paragraph C says that <exp>another way that Jefferson and Hamilton disagreed was on the power-sharing relationship between the states and the federal government</exp>. From this, it can be determined that paragraph C is the paragraph that discusses Jefferson's and Hamilton's beliefs about what the relationship between the states and the central government should be. Paragraph C is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word' essay-file='ASW02P4.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the transition phrase in paragraph B that announces that the first point of disagreement between Jefferson and Hamilton will be discussed.</question-text><explain-text>Paragraph B begins with <exp>one way that Jefferson and Hamilton disagreed&#8230;</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the transition phrase <exp>one way</exp> announces that the first point of disagreement between Jefferson and Hamilton will be discussed. <exp>One way</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word' essay-file='ASW02P5.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the transition word in paragraph B that indicates that Jefferson and Hamilton had contrasting ideas on what the basis of the economy should be.</question-text><explain-text>The second sentence in paragraph B states that <exp>Jefferson believed</exp> and <exp>Hamilton, however, believed</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the transition word <exp>however</exp> indicates that Jefferson and Hamilton had contrasting ideas on what the basis of the economy should be. <exp>However</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word' essay-file='ASW02P6.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the transition phrase in paragraph C that announces that the second point of disagreement between Jefferson and Hamilton will be discussed.</question-text><explain-text>Paragraph C begins with <exp>another way that Jefferson and Hamilton disagreed</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the transitional phrase <exp>another way</exp> announces that the second point of disagreement between Jefferson and Hamilton will be discussed. <exp>Another way</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word' essay-file='ASW02P7.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the transition phrase in paragraph C that indicates that Jefferson and Hamilton had contrasting ideas on the power-sharing arrangement between the states and the central government.</question-text><explain-text>The second sentence in paragraph C states that <exp>Jefferson, a Republican, believed</exp>, and the next sentence goes on the state that <exp>Federalist Hamilton, on the other hand, believed</exp>.  From this, it can be determined that the transition phrase <exp>on the other hand</exp> indicates that Jefferson and Hamilton had contrasting ideas on the power-sharing arrangement between the states and the central government.  <exp>On the other hand</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question></question-list>