<?xml version='1.0'?><question-list type='write' notes-file='ASW06N.xml' essay-file='ASW06P0.xml'><question type='select.errors' essay-file='ASW06P1.xml' skills='8-14'><question-text>Paragraph A contains 4 errors in grammar and sentence structure. Click on the errors in this paragraph.</question-text><error-list><explain-text>This sentence has two main clauses <exp>I am&#8230;</exp> and <exp>I read&#8230;</exp>, which are connected with a comma. A comma cannot be used to connect two main clauses. To correct this error, you can either change the comma to a semicolon or a period or add a coordinate conjunction such as <exp>and</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the verb <exp>is</exp> has two subjects, <exp>Most</exp> and <exp>it</exp>. To correct this error, you can omit <exp>it</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the adverb <exp>enjoyably</exp> is used to describe the noun <exp>type</exp>. An adjective should be used to describe a noun. To correct this error, you can change <exp>enjoyably</exp> to <exp>enjoyable</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>This sentence uses <exp>as well as</exp> with <exp>both</exp>. The correct paired conjunction is <exp>both&#8230;and</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>as well as</exp> to <exp>and</exp>.</explain-text></error-list></question><question type='select.errors' essay-file='ASW06P2.xml' skills='8-14'><question-text>Paragraph B contains 4 errors in grammar and sentence structure. Click on the errors in this paragraph.</question-text><error-list><explain-text>In this sentence, the plural verb <exp>are</exp> does not agree with the singular subject <exp>reason</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>are</exp> to <exp>is</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the singular article <exp>a</exp> is used with the plural noun <exp>lots</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>a lots</exp> to either <exp>a lot</exp> or <exp>lots</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the singular quantifier <exp>one</exp> is used with the plural noun <exp>ways</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>ways</exp> to <exp>way</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>This one-clause sentence has a subject <exp>I</exp> and a verb <exp>am reading</exp> introduced by the subordinate clause connector <exp>While</exp>. A one-clause sentence cannot be introduced by a subordinate clause connector. To correct this error, you can change the period following <exp>magazine</exp> to a comma.</explain-text></error-list></question><question type='select.errors' essay-file='ASW06P3.xml' skills='8-14'><question-text>Paragraph C contains 4 errors in grammar and sentence structure. Click on the errors in this paragraph.</question-text><error-list><explain-text>In this sentence, the preposition <exp>for</exp> is accompanied by the verb <exp>enjoy</exp>. A preposition must be accompanied by a noun or pronoun. To correct this error, you can change <exp>enjoy</exp> to <exp>enjoyment</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the present participle adjective <exp>involving</exp> is used where the past participle adjective is needed. To correct this error, you can change <exp>involving</exp> to <exp>involved</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the possessive pronoun <exp>yours</exp> is used with the noun <exp>studies</exp>. A possessive adjective should be used with a noun. To correct this error, you can change <exp>yours</exp> to <exp>your</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the plural demonstrative adjective <exp>these</exp> is used with the singular noun <exp>way</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>these</exp> to <exp>this</exp>.</explain-text></error-list></question><question type='select.errors' essay-file='ASW06P4.xml' skills='8-14'><question-text>Paragraph D contains 4 errors in grammar and sentence structure. Click on the errors in this paragraph.</question-text><error-list><explain-text>This sentence contains the present tense verb <exp>are</exp> and the past tense verb <exp>enjoyed</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>enjoyed</exp> to <exp>enjoy</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the singular article <exp>a</exp> is used with the plural noun <exp>periods</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>periods</exp> to <exp>period</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the possessive pronoun <exp>mine</exp> is used with the noun <exp>studies</exp>. A possessive adjective should be used with a noun. To correct this error, you can change <exp>mine</exp> to <exp>my</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the adjective <exp>important</exp> is used with the preposition <exp>with</exp>. A noun or pronoun should be used with a preposition. To correct this error, you can change <exp>important</exp> to <exp>importance</exp>.</explain-text></error-list></question></question-list>