<?xml version='1.0'?><question-list type='write' passage-file='ASW03RP.xml' audio-file='ASW03.mp3' script-file='ASW03LS.xml' notes-file='ASW03N.xml' essay-file='ASW03P0.xml'><question type='select.errors' essay-file='ASW03P1.xml' skills='6'><question-text>Paragraph A contains 3 errors in grammar and sentence structure. Click on the errors in this paragraph.</question-text><error-list><explain-text>This sentence has two main clauses <exp>the reading passage presents</exp> and <exp>the listening passage presents</exp>, which are connected with a comma. A comma cannot be used to connect two main clauses. To correct this error, you can either change the comma to a semi-colon or add a coordinate conjunction such as <exp>and</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the article <exp>a</exp> is accompanied by the verb <exp>discuss</exp>. An article should be accompanied by a noun. To correct this error, you can change <exp>discuss</exp> to <exp>discussion</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the countable singular noun <exp>decision</exp> requires an article. To correct this error, you can change <exp>final decision</exp> to <exp>a final decision</exp> or <exp>the final decision</exp>.</explain-text></error-list></question><question type='select.errors' essay-file='ASW03P2.xml' skills='7'><question-text>Paragraph B contains 7 errors in grammar and sentence structure. Click on the errors in this paragraph.</question-text><error-list><explain-text>In this sentence, the helping verb <exp>was</exp> is followed by the base form <exp>face</exp>. In this case, a form of the verb <exp>be</exp> should be followed by a present participle. To correct this error, you can change <exp>face</exp> to <exp>facing</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the adverb <exp>seriously</exp> is describing the noun <exp>tardiness</exp>. An adjective should describe a noun. To correct this error, you can change <exp>seriously</exp> to <exp>serious</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>This one-clause sentence has a subject <exp>problem</exp> and a verb <exp>was</exp> introduced by the subordinate clause connector <exp>Because</exp>. A one-clause sentence cannot be introduced by a subordinate clause connector. To correct this error, you can change the period following <exp>serious</exp> to a comma and remove the capitalization on <exp>The</exp> in the following sentence.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the first verb <exp>asked</exp> is in the past tense, and the second verb <exp>do</exp> is in the present tense. To correct this error, you can change <exp>do</exp> to <exp>did</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the plural verb <exp>were</exp> does not agree with the singular subject <exp>One</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>were</exp> to <exp>was</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the singular pronoun <exp>he</exp> refers to the plural noun <exp>employees</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>he</exp> to <exp>they</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the word <exp>due</exp> is part of the expression <exp>due to</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>due tardiness</exp> to <exp>due to tardiness</exp>.</explain-text></error-list></question><question type='select.errors' essay-file='ASW03P3.xml' skills='7'><question-text>Paragraph C contains 6 errors in grammar and sentence structure. Click on the errors in this paragraph.</question-text><error-list><explain-text>In this sentence, the singular noun <exp>plan</exp> does not agree with the plural quantifier <exp>two</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>plan</exp> to <exp>plans</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the indefinite article <exp>a</exp> is used with the definite idea <exp>first possible solution</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>a</exp> to <exp>the</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the subordinate connector <exp>because</exp> is followed by a subject but is missing a verb. A subordinate clause connector should be followed by a subject and a verb. To correct this error, you can change <exp>this not</exp> to <exp>this was not</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the modal helping verb <exp>would</exp> is followed by the past participle <exp>lost</exp>. A modal helping verb should be followed by the base form of the verb. To correct this error, you can change <exp>lost</exp> to <exp>lose</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, the adverb <exp>valuably</exp> is used to describe the noun <exp>work</exp>. An adjective should be used to describe a noun. To correct this error, you can change <exp>valuably</exp> to <exp>valuable</exp>.</explain-text><explain-text>In this sentence, <exp>both</exp> is used with <exp>or</exp>. The correct paired conjunction is <exp>both&#8230;and</exp>. To correct this error, you can change <exp>or</exp> to <exp>and</exp>.</explain-text></error-list></question></question-list>