<?xml version='1.0'?><essay><question-text>Salary increases and promotions to new positions are not the only ways to reward employees for good work. What other rewards for good work can be effective in encouraging further good work? Use specific examples to support your response.</question-text><sample-answer-text>A.<tab/><exp><key>When employees in an organization do good work, various types of rewards can be used. Rewards such as increased salaries or promotions to higher positions are certainly well-recognized rewards, but these rewards are not always feasible for a company to give. From my work as a computer programmer in a rather small technology company, I have seen that various other kinds of rewards can be used to encourage good performance. I have also seen how important and effective these rewards can be. Other types of rewards for good work that a company might want to consider are recognition for accomplishments and increased authority for strong performers.</key></exp><br/>B.<tab/>One type of reward for good work that might be considered by an organization is recognition. The positive effects of using recognition as a reward should not be overlooked. When a certain employee has performed well and the organization makes the effort to reward this strong performance through recognition, this can have a positive effect on the employee. The employee selected for recognition will appreciate the acclaim and will want to continue to perform well in order to continue to be worthy of it. However, it is not just the employee who will benefit from the recognition; the employee's coworkers will benefit, too. The employee's coworkers will understand the value that the organization places on good performance and will want to work to achieve recognition of their own. Thus, the effect on the organization as a whole of the use of recognition as a reward for strong performance is positive.<br/>C.<tab/>A second type of reward, in addition to the recognition of good work, is the awarding of increased authority to employees who have performed well. Employees who have performed well may be given increased authority within their current positions as a reward, and this control could be in a number of different forms. Employees could perhaps be given the authority to make decisions that previously had to be approved or the authority to work in a way that is less closely supervised. In addition, employees could be given the authority to choose which projects or tasks they will work on. This type of reward can go far to increase the satisfaction of employees in their current jobs.<br/>D.<tab/>Rewards for good work in an organization are vital if the organization wants to encourage more and better work throughout the organization. These rewards do not always need to take the form of increased salary, which can be overly costly to the organization, or promotions, which can prove disruptive if hardworking employees are constantly moving to new positions. Instead, rewards such as recognition for strong performance or the awarding of additional authority within current positions can go far to demonstrate that good performance is valued by an organization.</sample-answer-text></essay>