<?xml version='1.0'?><question-list type='write' passage-file='ASW01RP.xml' audio-file='ASW01.mp3' script-file='ASW01LS.xml' notes-file='ASW01N.xml' essay-file='ASW01P0.xml'><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW01P1.xml' skills='4'><question-text>Click on the sentence that shows how the ideas in the reading passage and the listening passage are related.<br/>Scroll the passage to find the answer.</question-text><explain-text>The first sentence says that <exp>the reading passage presents</exp> and <exp>the listening passage focuses</exp>. From this, it can be determined that this sentence shows how the ideas in the reading passage and the listening passage are related. The first sentence is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.paragraph' essay-file='ASW01P2.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the paragraph that discusses a problem faced by a certain university.<br/>Scroll the passage to find the answer.</question-text><explain-text>The first sentence of paragraph B states that <exp>a certain campus had a big problem</exp>. From this, it can be determined that paragraph B discusses a problem faced by a certain university. Paragraph B is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.paragraph' essay-file='ASW01P3.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the paragraph that discusses the results when one solution was implemented.<br/>Scroll the passage to see all of the paragraphs.</question-text><explain-text>The second sentence of paragraph C discusses what happened <exp>when the plan was implemented and parking fees were doubled</exp>. From this, it can be determined that paragraph C discusses the results when one solution was implemented. Paragraph C is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word' essay-file='ASW01P4.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the transition phrase in paragraph B that shows that examples of how officials could get money will follow.</question-text><explain-text>The second sentence in paragraph B mentions <exp>ways to raise money, such as increasing tuition and other fees and decreasing salaries and other costs</exp>. From this, it can be determined that <exp>such as</exp> is the transition phrase that shows that examples of how officials could get money will follow. You should therefore click on <exp>such as</exp>.</explain-text></question><question type='select.sentence' essay-file='ASW01P5.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the transition sentence that shows how an idea in paragraph B and an idea in paragraph C are related.<br/>Scroll the passage to find the answer.</question-text><explain-text><exp>The assumption</exp> is the idea at the end of paragraph B, and the first sentence of paragraph C refers to <exp>this assumption</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the first sentence of paragraph C shows how an idea in paragraph B and an idea in paragraph C are related. The first sentence of paragraph C is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question><question type='select.word' essay-file='ASW01P6.xml' skills='5'><question-text>Click on the transition phrase in paragraph C that shows that examples of methods that students use to get to school will follow.</question-text><explain-text>The second sentence in paragraph C mentions <exp>alternate ways to get to school</exp> and then goes on to state that <exp>the students, for instance, started carpooling, walking, bicycling, or taking the bus</exp>. From this, it can be determined that the transition phrase <exp>for instance</exp> shows that examples of methods that the students use to get to school will follow. <exp>For instance</exp> is therefore the best answer to this question.</explain-text></question></question-list>