<?xml version='1.0'?><essay><question-text>In some organizations, promotions are based on seniority, while in other organizations, promotions are based on performance. Discuss the advantages of each position. Then indicate which position you think is best and why.</question-text><sample-answer-text><tab/>Various organizations have different criteria for promoting employees to higher positions. Some organizations seem to favor basing promotions on seniority, while other organizations generally seem to favor basing promotions on performance. Each of these criteria for promotion has a unique advantage.<br/><tab/>It can be argued that promotions based on seniority are well-deserved. An employee who has served for a long time within an organization has undoubtedly experienced a variety of circumstances in which the organization has found itself on a daily basis, and the employee has witnessed the effects of various types of decisions and policies on the organization. Such an employee, one with a long record of service to the organization, seems better able to prevent the repetition of past problems and to seek the repetition of past successes.<br/><tab/>However, it can also be argued that performance is a strong basis for promotion within an organization. A person who performs better than other employees in an organization is one who has earned a promotion; this person is also the one who should be in a position of leadership because he or she can lead others to work in a like manner through the positive example of strong performance.<br/><tab/>Of these two specific criteria for promotion, each has something to offer. A person who is promoted because of seniority brings knowledge of past successes and failures, while a person who is promoted because of strong performance brings leadership through good example. Though both of these seem to be important, and both leaders with seniority and leaders with strong performance are likely to be good leaders, if I had to choose one over the other as more important, I would choose the employee with the strong performance. This employee would be able to lead through the example of strong performance, and this would encourage others to work diligently in order to be promoted. </sample-answer-text></essay>