<?xml version='1.0'?><essay><question-text>Some people are very organized, while other people are not so organized. Which type of person are you? Support your response with specific examples.</question-text><sample-answer-text><tab/>Some people are always highly organized, while others are always disorganized. I find that I am a rather particular combination of the two: The degree to which I am organized is vastly different at work and at home.<br/><tab/>On the job, I am one of the most organized people around. My desk is always neat, unlike the desks of many of my coworkers, and every paper is always in the appropriate file. When people at work need information, I am the one they call on because they know that I am the one who can put my hands on the necessary piece of information quickly. Last week, for example, my boss announced at a meeting that we all needed to research a particular contract that had a problem in it. I was immediately able to explain to my boss that I had not only the final contract but also all of the preliminary versions of the contract and all of the other supporting documents used in preparing the contract, together in one folder. Thus, instead of having the entire department work on reconstructing how this particular contract had been created, I was easily able to supply all of the necessary information quickly because I am so organized at work.<br/><tab/>My behavior at home, however is quite unlike my behavior at work. I have numerous examples that show how disorganized I am at home. When bills come in the mail, they seem to disappear on their own, and it is easy for me to make mistakes in my handling of bills. If I want to take a trip, my passport could be anywhere. If I want to charge something, my credit card could be anywhere. If I am ready to leave in my car, my car keys could be anywhere.<br/><tab/>It may seem unusual to others that I can be so organized at work and then not make any effort to be as highly organized at home. This way of living seems perfectly normal to me. When I am in the office, this is where I work, and work to me needs to be organized. However, when I am at home, this is where I like to relax, and trying to keep organized is not relaxing and is therefore not part of my home life. </sample-answer-text></essay>